[
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The province of Fars has been, for over two millennia, a cultural and civilizational (and linguistic) center in what is today what country?",
    "answer": "IRAN",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "She is Talia in the Italian fairy tale Sun, Moon, and Talia ( Sole, Luna, e Talia ), while the Brothers Grimm named her Briar Rose (Dornröschen), and Disney calls her Aurora. By what name is this princess best known today?",
    "answer": "SLEEPING BEAUTY",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "A treaty signed in London in December of 1921 ended the war for independence of what revolutionary state, which would then become a self-governing dominion within the British Commonwealth in 12 months (and ultimately, a sovereign state fifteen years later)?",
    "answer": "IRISH REPUBLIC",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Evolving from the Latin for star , this term is used mostly today in reference to a specific time scale, derived from the Earth's rotation period measured in relation to a fixed star.",
    "answer": "SIDEREAL",
    "percent_correct": 18.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Avery was the name of both the mother and the famously illegitimate son of what television sitcom's title character?",
    "answer": "MURPHY BROWN",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the Frenchman responsible for the design of these items. Click here",
    "answer": "PHILIPPE STARCK",
    "percent_correct": 9.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "In the Bible, this angel appears to the prophet Daniel, interpreting his visions, and to Mary, annunciating the conception and birth of Jesus. In Islam, he visited Muhammad and delivered the prophet's first divine revelation (sura 96 of the Quran).",
    "answer": "GABRIEL",
    "percent_correct": 87.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Give the most common name for the scientific instrument pictured here. Click here",
    "answer": "GEIGER COUNTER",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "After the suicide of lead singer Ian Curtis, the members of the English rock band Joy Division re-formed to create what other influential band?",
    "answer": "NEW ORDER",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The traditional baroque suite might begin with a French ouverture , normally followed by four core dances, originating from Germany, France, Spain, and Britain/Ireland, respectively (other galanteries were also common, following the third movement). Name any one of these four core suite movements.",
    "answer": "ALLEMANDE, COURANTE, SARABANDE, GIGUE",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "In January of 1943, shortly before the retreat of German forces from Stalingrad, Allied leaders (notably minus Joseph Stalin) met to discuss matters of diplomacy, resource allocation, and war tactics -- and, of greatest historical significance, to declare the Allied demand of \"unconditional surrender.\" This conference took place in what city, which already had a separate, unrelated association to WWII?",
    "answer": "CASABLANCA",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In Major League Baseball, from 1991 to 1998, six of the eight National League Cy Young Awards were bestowed among three members of which team (a seventh was awarded to one of those three while playing for another team)?",
    "answer": "ATLANTA BRAVES",
    "percent_correct": 65.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the actor cropped from the left edge of this screenshot. Click here",
    "answer": "KAREEM ABDUL-JABBAR",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The military statue officially named the Marine Corps War Memorial , which sits outside the walls of the Arlington National Cemetery, is also known by a name that references what WWII battle (which is strongly evoked by the features of the statue)?",
    "answer": "IWO JIMA",
    "percent_correct": 86.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The letters in the CMYK color model refer to the inks used in some four-color printing. The K refers to the black ink of the key plate ; to what colors do the other three letters refer?",
    "answer": "CYAN, MAGENTA, YELLOW",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What Italian dish, very thinly sliced raw meat or fish typically served with greens and/or a light sauce, was created by Giuseppe Cipriani of Harry's Bar in Venice, and is named after a Venetian painter noted for prominent use of red in his works?",
    "answer": "CARPACCIO",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are variations of an automobile designed and first produced by what car manufacturer? Click here",
    "answer": "LOTUS",
    "percent_correct": 9.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The primary protagonists in the 10th and latest (November 2013) main installment of the video game franchise Call of Duty are U.S. Special Operations forces, trained to conduct covert missions behind enemy lines. In the game, this faction of soldiers is officially known as Task Force: STALKER , but is better known as what?",
    "answer": "GHOSTS",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Give the French term most commonly used for the little colorful items in this photograph. Click here",
    "answer": "NONPAREILS",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Father John O'Connor, a Roman Catholic priest in the northern England city of Bradford, provided the basis for the main character in series of detective short stories by what author and lay theologian?",
    "answer": "G.K. CHESTERTON",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "With revenue of over $45 billion in 2013, roughly seven times larger than the Las Vegas Strip's, the casino market of this city is the world's largest, by far.",
    "answer": "MACAU",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "A biological episode known as a vasovagal response may lead to what is termed medically as syncope , but is better known colloquially as what?",
    "answer": "FAINTING/PASSING OUT",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The shocking November 1974 murders by Ronald DeFeo, Jr., of his parents and four of his siblings provided the basis, in part, for what controversial 1977 novel and subsequent film series?",
    "answer": "THE AMITYVILLE HORROR",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Serravalle, Borgo Maggiore, Fiorentino, and Acquaviva, along with the namesake capital, are among the largest castelli in what Most Serene republic?",
    "answer": "SAN MARINO",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Originally a vat room with hop storage for London's Woodyard Brewery, the building known presently as the Donmar Warehouse is today used primarily for what other purpose?",
    "answer": "THEATRE",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Identify the Democratic U.S. Senator, Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, who is the Senate's most senior member (and thus, as a member of the majority party, the President pro tempore).",
    "answer": "PATRICK LEAHY",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The series of military conflicts known as the Carnatic Wars, which took place from 1746 to 1763, saw British-controlled forces battle French-controlled forces in territories which are today a part of what nation?",
    "answer": "INDIA",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the party-loving country music superstar, pictured here, who had two separate albums reach #1 on the Billboard country albums chart in 2013 ( Spring Break…Here to Party and Crash My Party ). Click here",
    "answer": "LUKE BRYAN",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Identify the building at the right in this photograph. Click here",
    "answer": "ASTRODOME",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Esther Summerson, the [spoiler alert] illegitimate daughter of Lady Honoria Dedlock and Captain James Hawdon, is the heroine of which Charles Dickens novel, as well as the only first-person narrator in any of his books who is female?",
    "answer": "BLEAK HOUSE",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The evergreen oak tree quercus suber , native to southwest Europe and northwest Africa, is the world's primary source for what common water-resistant material?",
    "answer": "CORK",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Grave Descend , Odds On , Drug of Choice , and Easy Go were among the paperback suspense thrillers written by what prolific American novelist (and filmmaker and television producer), under the pen name of John Lange, while a student at Harvard Medical School in the late 1960s?",
    "answer": "MICHAEL CRICHTON",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify this Trojan priest, shown here agonizing with his sons. Click here",
    "answer": "LAOCOÖN",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Delbert Mann won the 1955 Oscar for Best Director for Marty , his film debut, and Jerome Robbins repeated the feat for 1961's West Side Story . Since then, four additional men have won Best Director Oscars for their film directing debuts -- name any one of the four.",
    "answer": "ROBERT REDFORD, JAMES L. BROOKS, KEVIN COSTNER, SAM MENDES",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Cleave is a word in English, known as an auto-antonym , with two synonyms which are themselves antonyms (\"adhere\" and \"separate\"). What other such word is an auto-antonym that can mean \"garnish\" or \"prune\"?",
    "answer": "TRIM or TOP",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The first formal arms control accord established during the Cold War was a treaty entered into force in 1961, prohibiting military activity, mineral mining, nuclear explosions and disposal of nuclear material, as well as supporting scientific research and environmental protections, where?",
    "answer": "ANTARCTICA",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "British musicians David Stewart and Annie Lennox were the members of what Grammy-winning duo, popular in the 1980s?",
    "answer": "EURYTHMICS",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The literal translation in English of the name Beelzebub provides the title for what novel first published in 1954?",
    "answer": "LORD OF THE FLIES",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "From 1787 until 1800, the area covered by the present-day U.S. states of Ohio, Indiana, Michigan, Illinois, and Wisconsin, as well as a part of Minnesota, together formed an organized political division of the U.S. with what name?",
    "answer": "NORTHWEST TERRITORY",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In December of 1967, Louis Washkansky, a native Lithuanian resident of Cape Town, South Africa, achieved renown as a pioneering recipient of what?",
    "answer": "HEART TRANSPLANT",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Heard here is an excerpt from the opening of what television series? (7 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "DRAGNET",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "What is the geometric term, from the Latin for \"round protuberance\", for a Euclidean surface generated by revolving a circle, in 3D space, around an axis on the same plane as the circle. Colloquially, the surface could be described as \"doughnut-shaped\".",
    "answer": "TORUS",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What is the most significant distinction shared by Cahawba, Alabama; Bodie, California; Dogtown, Massachusetts; and Pripyat, Ukraine?",
    "answer": "GHOST TOWNS",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "This action film series' hyper-violent 2008 installment, which is named simply after the title character despite being the fourth in the franchise, is currently banned in Burma (to the surprise of no one who has seen the film).",
    "answer": "RAMBO",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "While they're better known locally as the Intifadat-al-Istiqlal , the 2005 demonstrations in Lebanon, triggered by the assassination of Prime Minister Rafik Hariri, are known internationally as what -- a term coined by a U.S. State Department official in reference to Lebanon's national emblem?",
    "answer": "CEDAR REVOLUTION",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "In the history of the Grammy awards, three songs have won Record of the Year or Song of the Year whose titles reference an American city (New Orleans, San Francisco, Philadelphia). What is the only song to do so whose title references a Brazilian neighborhood?",
    "answer": "THE GIRL FROM IPANEMA",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "This term, first introduced in the early 20th c. by English archaeologist and palace of Knossos excavator Arthur Evans, is defined primarily as relating to the culture and civilization that existed during the Bronze Age on the island of Crete. What is the term?",
    "answer": "MINOAN",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Identify the former NBA star and basketball Hall of Famer in this image. Click here",
    "answer": "JERRY WEST",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Applied with differing definitions in various sports, this term is also used in theatre to describe the act of taking down the set after a show's closing.",
    "answer": "STRIKE",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The scientific term for white blood cells is leukocytes ; what is the analogous term for red blood cells?",
    "answer": "ERYTHROCYTES",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Josiah Bartlett, the American statesman who served as New Hampshire delegate to the Continental Congress, and later as the state's governor, was a real person, but is the direct ascendant of a fictional main character from what television series?",
    "answer": "THE WEST WING",
    "percent_correct": 83.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The Lessons Learnt and Reconciliation Commission was an office of inquiry established in May 2010, shortly after the conclusion of a destructive  26-year civil war, by Mahinda Rajapaksa, the president of what country?",
    "answer": "SRI LANKA",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the subject of this portrait from c. 1498, by Fra Bartolomeo. Click here",
    "answer": "GIROLAMO SAVONAROLA",
    "percent_correct": 11.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Bert and Nan, and Flossie and Freddie, were the title characters of what series of 72 children's novels, the first of which was published in 1904?",
    "answer": "BOBBSEY TWINS",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "One of the few individuals with both an Erdos number (of 5) and a Bacon number (of 2) is what actress, by virtue of a psychology paper written while a student at Harvard University, and her appearance as thirteen-year-old Marty in 1996's Beautiful Girls ?",
    "answer": "NATALIE PORTMAN",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the man who famously sang, in a #1 hit from 1961, of girlfriends in Mexico, Alaska, Berlin, Hong Kong, and Waikiki (and elsewhere) -- whom he would visit while travelin'.",
    "answer": "RICKY NELSON",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The country of Indonesia is an archipelago consisting of over 17,500 islands. Of those, it shares three with other countries. Name two of those three islands .",
    "answer": "BORNEO, NEW GUINEA (PAPUA), TIMOR",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "While there are a number of institutions in the United States called Trinity College, the total decreased by one in 1924 when North Carolina's Trinity College changed its name to what, after receiving a major private endowment from a prominent American industrialist?",
    "answer": "DUKE UNIVERSITY",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Identify the former Serb military leader, Chief of Staff of the Bosnian Serb Army, who is the man believed most responsible for the 1992-96 Siege of Sarajevo, as well as the July 1995 Srebrenica massacre (along with Radovan Karadžić).",
    "answer": "RATKO MLADIĆ",
    "percent_correct": 14.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What was the most notable and particular circumstance shared by the respective authors during the writing of Le Morte d'Arthur , Don Quixote , Pilgrim's Progress , Our Lady of the Flowers ( Notre Dame des Fleurs ), and Mein Kampf ?",
    "answer": "IMPRISONED",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In January of 1906, a U.S. patent was granted for an \"Apparatus for Treating Air\" to what American engineer and businessman, whose name remains prominent in the field via his namesake corporation?",
    "answer": "WILLIS CARRIER",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the pop music superstar who adopted a stage name using her mother's maiden name, versus her own last name, in order to avoid confusion with a 2000 Academy Award nominee.",
    "answer": "KATY PERRY",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Of the four humors, which composed a commonly held view of the human body before the advent of modern medicine, which one corresponded to winter, and the classical element water ?",
    "answer": "PHLEGM",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "This photo shows the northern end of an area known (in English) as \"Museum Island\". What is the local name for the taller object at the left, in the distance? Click here",
    "answer": "FERNSEHTURM",
    "percent_correct": 12.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "After almost 7,000 one-hour daily episodes, whose television talk show aired its final program in September of 1996, giving it the longest continuous run of any syndicated talk show in U.S. television history (a distinction it still holds today)?",
    "answer": "PHIL DONAHUE",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Apart from the first Pomp and Circumstance March , the best-known work of English composer Edward Elgar is likely a set of fourteen variations which are formally titled Variations on an Original Theme for Orchestra , but are better known as what?",
    "answer": "ENIGMA VARIATIONS",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Name the actress currently performing on Broadway as Mama Morton in the musical Chicago , the unprecedented third different lead she has played in the show (having previously starred as Velma Kelly and as Roxie Hart).",
    "answer": "BEBE NEUWIRTH",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What archaic English word, today associated most closely with Ebenezer Scrooge, was originally defined as someone (or something) designed to mislead and deceive.",
    "answer": "HUMBUG",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Identify the gentleman operating the vehicle here. Click here",
    "answer": "TOM SLICK",
    "percent_correct": 6.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The chemical simethicone is the active ingredient in medications normally administered for the treatment of pain and discomfort caused by what?",
    "answer": "GAS",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Lafayette National Park, which was created in 1919 on Mount Desert Island (and other nearby islands) off the Atlantic coast, was renamed what in 1929, in honor of colonists who settled the area in the 17th and early 18th centuries?",
    "answer": "ACADIA NATIONAL PARK",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Owned today by Pinnacle Foods, what is the best-selling food item in the United States named in honor of Abraham Lincoln?",
    "answer": "LOG CABIN SYRUP",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In finance, a measure of financial performance calculated as a change in operational monetary balance (over a given period), minus capital expenditures, is often abbreviated FCF . What do the letters in FCF stand for?",
    "answer": "FREE CASH FLOW",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "There are seven base units defined by the International System of Units (SI), through which all other SI units are derived. Which of the seven units measures the amount of a substance ? Specifically, it is defined as the amount of substance of a system which contains as many elementary units as there are atoms in 0.012 kg of carbon-12.",
    "answer": "MOLE",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The following are quotes from what film? \"Ooooh, I wish I were you! Gosh, to be able to smell your own ear!\"; \"It must wonderful to wake up in the morning and smell the coffee... in Brazil!\"; \"Uh, would you mind not bobbing your head? The, uh, orchestra keeps changing tempo.\"",
    "answer": "ROXANNE",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The Continental Army cavalry officer nicknamed \"Light-Horse Harry\"  was decorated for his actions during the American Revolution, and later served as Governor of Virginia, and U.S. Congressman. Despite all that, he's perhaps even better known today as the father of whom?",
    "answer": "ROBERT E. LEE",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This stone slab, currently on display in The Louvre, is associated with what Babylonian king? Click here",
    "answer": "HAMMURABI",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "In the form of classical Japanese dance theatre known as Noh , the only ornamentation on the stage is the kagami-ita , which is a particular object painted on the wood wall at the back of the rear stage area. What is this object?",
    "answer": "PINE TREE",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The title character of what German opera is, in fact, actually a devoted noblewoman named Leonore, disguised as a Spanish prison guard to rescue her wrongly incarcerated husband?",
    "answer": "FIDELIO",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Richard Belding was the principal of California's fictional Bayside High School on what teen-oriented television sitcom?",
    "answer": "SAVED BY THE BELL",
    "percent_correct": 88.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The events that came to be known as the \"Scramble for Africa\", and resulted in the colonization of nearly all of the continent by European colonial powers, were triggered to a large degree by an 1884-85 summit. This congregation is known as the West Africa Conference or Congo Conference, but was formally named (and is best known) after the city where it was held. Name that city.",
    "answer": "BERLIN",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are four extremely representative works from what English Romantic painter of the early 19th c.? Click here",
    "answer": "JOHN CONSTABLE",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Derived from the Greek word for \"heat\" (θάλπειν, thalpein ), this term in thermodynamics represents the quantity of total energy (heat content) of a system. It can be measured in joules, BTUs, or calories.",
    "answer": "ENTHALPY",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What term was coined by John Milton in Paradise Lost , used in the epic poem as the name for the high capital of Hell (though used today more generally to mean \"uproar\")?",
    "answer": "PANDEMONIUM",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Give the name, from Portuguese, for the sport being played in this photograph. Click here",
    "answer": "FUTSAL",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Vitruvius, a Roman architect, engineer, and builder from the 1st c. BC, shares his name with a prominent character from what popular 2014 film?",
    "answer": "THE LEGO MOVIE",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The English baronet and popinjay Sir Percy Blakeney is the true identity of what eponymous hero from a 1903 play and 1905 novel by Emma Orczy?",
    "answer": "THE SCARLET PIMPERNEL",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "This term from statistics, which sounds like a medical condition, is the degree of peakedness of a distribution of values. A high level of this would produce a distribution curve with fat tails and a distinct peak.",
    "answer": "KURTOSIS",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What is the fine-textured long-grained rice, grown primarily in the outer Himalayas where it has been cultivated for centuries, whose name translates from Hindi as \"queen of fragrance\"?",
    "answer": "BASMATI",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Former members of the rock bands The Byrds, Buffalo Springfield, and The Hollies gained even greater success in the late 1960s and 1970s as members of what other influential band?",
    "answer": "CROSBY, STILLS & NASH (& YOUNG)",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "1988's The Sackett Companion , published a few months after the author's death, is a guided tour through the stories and background of the seventeen western novels featuring the fictional Sackett family. Who wrote these novels, and this final companion book?",
    "answer": "LOUIS L'AMOUR",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "In mathematics, a Mersenne prime is defined as a prime number of the form 2 n - 1 . 3, 7, and 31 are the first three Mersenne primes; what is the fourth?",
    "answer": "127",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "While the \"main\" Alps are in Europe, another separate mountain range with that name -- with a distinguishing forename, and formally a component of a larger cordillera called the Great Dividing Range -- is the highest in what country?",
    "answer": "AUSTRALIA",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Philadelphia's historic Bellevue-Stratford Hotel achieved international newsworthiness in July of 1976, by virtue of its hosting what organization?",
    "answer": "AMERICAN LEGION",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The machine pictured here, which was first produced in early 1980 and quickly created the signature sound of hip hop and electronic music of the era, was manufactured by what musical electronics company (whose name has been edited from the image)? Click here",
    "answer": "ROLAND",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "An investor may sell a financial contract (e.g. a share) that she does not actually own, with the expectation that its price will fall, at which point it can then be purchased, resulting in profit. This investment activity is most commonly known as what?",
    "answer": "SHORTING",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Mozart's Symphony No. 41 in C major , the longest of his symphonies as well as his last, is known today by what pantheonic nickname?",
    "answer": "JUPITER SYMPHONY",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "The series of ten August Wilson plays, which begins (chronologically) with Gem of the Ocean and ends with Radio Golf , and includes the Pulitzer Prize-winning The Piano Lesson and Fences , is collectively known as a Cycle named after what city? It is where the playwright was born, and where nine of the ten plays were set.",
    "answer": "PITTSBURGH",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Relations between Greece and Turkey remain today dominated in large part by events, including a coup d'etat, which occurred in the summer of 1974 in what other country?",
    "answer": "CYPRUS",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What is the name for the style of breadcrumbs, common in the cuisine of Japan (from which the name comes), whose special processing includes baking the bread without crusts, usually by passing an electric current through the dough?",
    "answer": "PANKO",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The execution of a spectacular and dangerous dive, by senescent student Thornton Melon, wins the championship meet for Grand Lakes University during the climax of the 1986 film Back to School . What was the name of this legendary dive?",
    "answer": "TRIPLE LINDY",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the order of classical architecture highlighted in this image. Click here",
    "answer": "IONIC",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This trumpet, currently in the collection of the Smithsonian Institution, belonged to whom? Click here",
    "answer": "DIZZY GILLESPIE",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The First Sino-Japanese War in 1894-95, and the Russo-Japanese War of 1904-05, were both fought primarily over control of what sovereign state (which would then be under the dominion of Japan until the end of WWII)?",
    "answer": "KOREA",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The name of Jumbo the circus elephant was derived (probably) from the word jambo , which means \"hello\" in what language?",
    "answer": "SWAHILI",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What was the name of the character who appeared in exactly six episodes of the sitcom The Brady Bunch -- specifically (but not coincidentally), the final six episodes of the series' fifth and final season?",
    "answer": "OLIVER",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "From the years 1973 to 1980, American author Judy Blume published five novels for children or young adults, four of which have one-word titles (the fifth is Starring Sally J. Freedman as Herself ). Name any one of these four one-word-titled novels.",
    "answer": "DEENIE, BLUBBER, FOREVER, SUPERFUDGE",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Identify the firm, headquartered in Ludwigshafen, Germany, and founded in 1865 in Baden as an aniline and soda factory (manufacturing acids and soda for dyes). It is today the world's largest chemical company.",
    "answer": "BASF",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Name the bartending tool pictured here, which is used to measure liquor, and which shares its name with a particular mast of a large sailing ship. Click here",
    "answer": "JIGGER",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Whose woods these are I think I know is the first line of a poem whose fourth and final stanza ends with what exact seven-word line? (Note: Must be precise. )",
    "answer": "AND MILES TO GO BEFORE I SLEEP",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "While the First Crusade, at the end of the 11th c., began as an effort to defend the Byzantine Empire from invading Muslim Seljuks, it quickly switched its primary goal to the conquest of what city (which it achieved in July of 1099, quite bloodily)?",
    "answer": "JERUSALEM",
    "percent_correct": 65.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the term, French for \"workshop\", which is used in English for the studio of a principal designer or artist with a number of apprentices, students, and assistants. By extension, today the term also applies to the method of art instruction which utilizes this private training model.",
    "answer": "ATELIER",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "In what has been her only significant acting credit, Rachel Dennison, the younger sister of country music superstar Dolly Parton, played Doralee Rhodes (a role created by Dolly) in what television sitcom, which ran in two versions from 1982-83, and 1986-88?",
    "answer": "9 TO 5",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Columbus, Canton, Cleveland, Clinton, Madison, Greenville, Philadelphia, Meridian, and Oxford are all cities in what U.S. state which is not Ohio?",
    "answer": "MISSISSIPPI",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Billionaire Nawaz Sharif, chairman of the integrated steel manufacturer Ittefaq Group, is one of the wealthiest men in, and the Prime Minister of, what country?",
    "answer": "PAKISTAN",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "When the thirteen British colonies of North America declared independence in 1776, three of the colonies had capital cities which were named after British monarchs. Name any one of these three colonies & nascent U.S. states.",
    "answer": "MARYLAND, SOUTH CAROLINA, VIRGINIA",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Identify the beer whose name reflects its famous (but perhaps apocryphal) winning of the award as \"America's Best\" at the Chicago World's Fair in 1893.",
    "answer": "PABST BLUE RIBBON",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Who was the commander of the Apollo 14 manned lunar landing mission, which touched down on the moon on February 9, 1971? His role on the mission is perhaps best known for his bringing along a golf club, which he used to launch two balls on the moon's surface.",
    "answer": "ALAN SHEPARD",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the opera (24 seconds). Click here",
    "answer": "LOHENGRIN",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "On June 11, 1919, Sir Barton culminated the accomplishment of what feat -- which would not be repeated for eleven years, and still today has only been achieved eleven times in history (the latest in 1978)?",
    "answer": "(AMERICAN THOROUGHBRED) TRIPLE CROWN",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What is the most populous country in the world that has no land border with any other nation?",
    "answer": "JAPAN",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "All Growed Up was a special television movie, first airing on Nickelodeon in July 2001, which celebrated the 10th anniversary of what original Nicktoons series? The movie served as the pilot for the spinoff series All Grown Up! , which itself ran until 2008.",
    "answer": "RUGRATS",
    "percent_correct": 78.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The highest military decoration for gallantry and valor awarded by the armed forces of the British Commonwealth is what medal?",
    "answer": "VICTORIA CROSS",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The murder of an elderly pawnbroker and her younger half-sister is the titular felony in what classic novel, first published in 1866?",
    "answer": "CRIME AND PUNISHMENT",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is an electronic device used to convert direct current power to alternating current power. By what term is such a device most commonly known? Click here",
    "answer": "INVERTER",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The 1979-80 season of the National Hockey League saw the addition of four teams from the recently disbanded World Hockey Association. Of the four, the Hartford Whalers, Winnipeg Jets, and Quebec Nordiques eventually relocated to different cities. Identify the fourth team, which remains today in its 1979 home city.",
    "answer": "EDMONTON OILERS",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Identify the style of shoe represented by all of the examples pictured here, whose name comes not from an animal, but from a shoe worn by Ancient Roman magistrates. Click here",
    "answer": "MULE",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Roosevelt Field on Long Island, New York, was built in 1916 and named in honor of Theodore Roosevelt's son, Quentin. However, for most of its history, until it was closed in 1951, it was most closely associated with what other man? Today he is commemorated with a plaque in the mall that now sits at the site, near Express Men and The Disney Store.",
    "answer": "CHARLES LINDBERGH",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "There are four national capital cities on the African continent that begin with the letter \"K\". Please name any two .",
    "answer": "KAMPALA, KHARTOUM, KIGALI, KINSHASA",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Kyoto-born Shigeru Miyamoto, a graduate of the Kanazawa College of Art, is famous primarily as a result of his work while employed by what company?",
    "answer": "NINTENDO",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Among the many works of the French Romantic Hector Berlioz is what challenging and ambitious 1858 grand opera, the composer's take on Vergil's Aeneid ?",
    "answer": "LES TROYENS",
    "percent_correct": 13.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the song whose video was named by YouTube as the top trending video of 2013, and which is the biggest hit by a Norwegian artist on the Billboard singles chart since a-ha's \"Take on Me\" in 1985.",
    "answer": "THE FOX (WHAT DOES THE FOX SAY?)",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "According to Twitter, a Tweet by this person on March 2, 2014, is, with now over 3 million RTs, the most re-tweeted Tweet in the history of Twitter.",
    "answer": "ELLEN DEGENERES (@TheEllenShow)",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "With victories that include three gold medals in slalom events at the 1988 and 1992 Winter Olympics, one of the most successful competitive alpine skiers in history is what Italian, who remains today one of the most popular athletes in his country?",
    "answer": "ALBERTO TOMBA",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The common tool known as the Snellen chart , the primary legacy of 19th c. Dutch physician Hermann Snellen, is used to measure what?",
    "answer": "VISUAL ACUITY",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "What is the most common name for the fashion accessory pictured here? Click here",
    "answer": "CUMMERBUND",
    "percent_correct": 91.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "With seven-season runs, Mission: Impossible (1966-73) and The Avengers (1961-69) were the longest-running espionage-themed programs in American television history, until surpassed in 2010 by the eighth (and final) season of what fast-paced drama series?",
    "answer": "24",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Three different islands have particular associations with the life of Napoleon Bonaparte -- where he was born, where he was exiled in 1814, and where he died in 1821. Identify these three islands.",
    "answer": "CORSICA, ELBA, ST. HELENA",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "President Franklin Roosevelt appointed eight Justices to the U.S. Supreme Court during his tenure, which is the second-most in history. Which President appointed a total of ten during his two terms?",
    "answer": "GEORGE WASHINGTON",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What Central Asian country is, with an area of over one million mi 2 (2.7 million km 2 ), by far the world's largest landlocked country?",
    "answer": "KAZAKHSTAN",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Give the last word of each title of the three films which starred Matt Damon as CIA assassin Jason Bourne (note: answer will be three words).",
    "answer": "IDENTITY, SUPREMACY, ULTIMATUM",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Identify the type of tree pictured here, which gives its name to the National Preserve in southern Florida (adjacent to Everglades National Park) in which this photo was taken. Click here",
    "answer": "CYPRESS",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Name the man, a relative of the president (and later, territorial governor) of Hawaii, who founded the Hawaiian Pineapple Company in 1901, becoming known as the \"Pineapple King\".",
    "answer": "JAMES DOLE",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "One of the enduring works of the popular and successful (and notorious) English writer Edward Bulwer-Lytton is his 1834 novel describing the last days of what city?",
    "answer": "POMPEII",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In two different places in this image, a prefix is obscured by a red box. What is the prefix, from Greek for turn , that is obscured in both places (note: one answer only)? Click here",
    "answer": "TROPO",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What nickname, used previously and subsequently for unrelated items, was during World War I associated with a 420mm howitzer manufactured by armaments supplier Krupp for the German Imperial Army? At the time, it was the world's largest and most powerful artillery.",
    "answer": "BIG BERTHA",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The 1984 made-for-TV movie Solomon Northup's Odyssey , starring Avery Brooks, was based on material that also provided the source for what theatrical film?",
    "answer": "12 YEARS A SLAVE",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "While Frenchmen have won cycling's Tour de France 36 times, racers representing what other country have won it only twice -- but the most recent two, in 2012 and 2013?",
    "answer": "UNITED KINGDOM",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "List the five Great Lakes (the interconnected Laurentian Great Lakes of North America), in order, from smallest to largest, as measured by area.",
    "answer": "ONTARIO, ERIE, MICHIGAN, HURON, SUPERIOR",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL60",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "While the name for this popular Mediterranean dish is derived from Arabic for \"chilled,\" in Greek cuisine it is usually served warm. It often consists of layers of eggplant, minced lamb and tomatoes, and white sauce, which are cooked separately and then baked together.",
    "answer": "MOUSSAKA",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Joey, Pacey, Jen, and the title character were four sex-obsessed 15-year-old friends at Massachusetts's Capeside High School at the outset of what television drama series, which aired original episodes during the late 90s/early 00s?",
    "answer": "DAWSON'S CREEK",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Give the term for the style, originally a printed Indian calico, which features bright and colorful floral patterns on a plain light background. The term has expanded in contemporary usage to mean, in its adjectival form, \"cheap\" or \"gaudy\".",
    "answer": "CHINTZ",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In January of 2011, Tom Daugherty of Wesley Chapel, Florida, scored a 100 in a semifinal loss to Finland-born Mika Koivuniemi in the Las Vegas Tournament of Champions. In doing so, he set a record for the lowest score in a televised match, as well as the largest margin of loss (199). What was the sport?",
    "answer": "BOWLING",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Most humans, including basketball hall-of-famers Larry Bird, Scottie Pippen, and Patrick Ewing, the late Pope John Paul I, and every driver in the field of the Indianapolis 500-Mile Race, have (or had) how many vertebrae in their spinal columns?",
    "answer": "33",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Identify either of the royal dynastic houses that ruled France under the system (and during the period) known as the Ancien Régime ?",
    "answer": "VALOIS, BOURBON",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "A village in the English county of Somerset's Sedgemoor district gives its name to a food item which is the most popular of its type in the UK, and the second-most in the US (where it would probably also be first if not for a certain flat, baked dish). Name this village.",
    "answer": "CHEDDAR",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The term \"Pinoy\" is a gentilic used informally to refer to people of an ethnic group native to what country?",
    "answer": "PHILIPPINES",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "In any list of ancient cities that includes Stabiae, Oplontis, and Herculaneum, what other, better-known city would almost always be included?",
    "answer": "POMPEII",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "What is the greatest distinction shared by the bases for the Disney feature films Mission to Mars , The Country Bears , The Haunted Mansion , and Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl ?",
    "answer": "THEME PARK ATTRACTIONS",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Researchers at the University of Manchester won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 2010 for work on a revolutionary material, consisting of a single layer of hexagonally patterned carbon atoms just one atom thick, which is 100 times stronger than steel, and conducts electricity better than silicon. What is the official term for this groundbreaking substance?",
    "answer": "GRAPHENE",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Le Chat Noir , which opened in the Montmartre district of Paris in 1881, first assigned what term (from the Spanish for \"merry bowl\") to the small-scale entertainment, originally avant-garde and normally performed in cafes and pubs, which presents sketches, songs, speeches, and/or satires in a typical evening?",
    "answer": "CABARET",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "A four-step management methodology named the Deming cycle , after famed American statistician, consultant, and quality management guru W. Edwards Deming, is also commonly referred to by the initialism PDCA . Give any of the words represented by the letters in PDCA.",
    "answer": "PLAN, DO, CHECK, ACT/ADJUST",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "A genus of tree, a model of sport utility vehicle, a prominent Silicon Valley venture capital firm, and a Great Smoky mountain on the Tennessee/North Carolina border are all named after what man, the inventor of the Cherokee alphabet?",
    "answer": "SEQUOYAH",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "While five capital cities sit on the Baltic Sea, the most populous city with a Baltic port is not a national capital. What is that city?",
    "answer": "SAINT PETERSBURG, RUSSIA",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify this song. Click here",
    "answer": "JINGLE BELLS",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "A violent paternal child abduction, a silly but bitter and deadly feud among the Southern aristocratic Grangerford and Shepherdson households, and several scams by a con artist \"duke\" and \"dauphin\" pair are among the occurrences that form the plot of what  novel?",
    "answer": "THE ADVENTURES OF HUCKLEBERRY FINN",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The highest high tides and lowest low tides, called spring tides, are produced when the sun, moon and Earth are directly aligned, and the sun's and moon's gravitational forces are additive. What is the term for the opposite tides, which occur when the sun and moon are positioned with 90 degrees in between, and the tide range is at its minimum?",
    "answer": "NEAP TIDES",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The Beast on the Road , World Piece Tour , World Slavery Tour , and Somewhere on Tour were 1980s concert tours headlined by what heavy metal band?",
    "answer": "IRON MAIDEN",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "While variations exist, by far the most popular form of the competition known as a triathlon consists of what disciplines, in order ?",
    "answer": "SWIMMING, CYCLING, RUNNING",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Per the common name for the work of art pictured here, what was the homeland of this expiring gentleman? Click here",
    "answer": "GAUL/GALATIA",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Name the woman who is missing from the otherwise complete set in this photo, taken in April, 2013. Click here",
    "answer": "NANCY REAGAN",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The prefix blepharo- is used for certain medical conditions that affect what specific part of the human body? Examples include blepharitis , blepharospasm , and Blepharo naso facial syndrome .",
    "answer": "EYELID/EYE LASH",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "This actress and comedian is the only person ever to have won an Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, Tony, and Nickelodeon Kids' Choice Award. She won five KCAs between 1988 and 1994 for Favorite Movie Actress, though she was also well-known during this period for her role on a science fiction television series.",
    "answer": "WHOOPI GOLDBERG",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Name the ancient port city, named perhaps for a son of Noah, or the mother of Andromeda, which since 1950 has formally been a part of the Israeli city of Tel Aviv.",
    "answer": "JAFFA/YAFO",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In each season from 1993 to 1997, two unrelated members of the NFL All-Pro first team shared a last name -- a running back and a cornerback. Give the last name shared by these two players.",
    "answer": "SANDERS",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Give the name of the dish, a seared and roasted tenderloin steak usually served with a bearnaise or other wine sauce, which is typically ordered for a table of two. It was created in the 1820s by the personal chef of a French diplomat and rhetorician of the modern Romantic school.",
    "answer": "CHATEAUBRIAND",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Published in 1848, Camille ( La Dame aux camélias ) is the most popular and best-known work from what filial writer and dramatist?",
    "answer": "ALEXANDRE DUMAS, FILS",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Prokaryote is the term for a single-celled organism that lacks a distinct nucleus. What is the parallel term for a single- or multi-celled organism whose cells contain distinct nuclei?",
    "answer": "EUKARYOTE",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Of the twelve Christian apostles in the canonical gospels of the New Testament, name the one who was first to die, as well as the only one not to achieve sainthood in the Roman Catholic Church?",
    "answer": "JUDAS ISCARIOT",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What is the term for the predominant class of battleship in service during the first decades of the 20th c., which takes its name from that of a revolutionary British Royal Navy vessel which first sailed in 1906? During the era, her name became synonymous with the term \"battleship\" itself.",
    "answer": "DREADNOUGHT",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The process known as cryodesiccation (or more colloquially, freeze-drying), involves two thermodynamic phase transitions, the first of which is the freezing of the substance. What is the other transition, which converts the frozen water in the substance to vapor via a strong vacuum?",
    "answer": "SUBLIMATION",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "In a famous 1929 novel—spoiler alert!—the main character, a German soldier named Paul Bäumer, dies at the end. How does the army's situation report describe that day?",
    "answer": "ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Identify the baseball fan whose face is obscured in this montage. Click here",
    "answer": "BILLY CRYSTAL",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Barbara Hutton, the serial bride and debutante derisively dubbed \"Poor Little Rich Girl\" during the Great Depression (and later), was an heiress to the E.F. Hutton fortune, via her father, but more famously to the fortune of what other company, via her maternal grandfather?",
    "answer": "WOOLWORTH",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Nymphéas is the title of an extremely famous and influential series of impressionist Givernois paintings, most of which were done in the first quarter of the twentieth century. What is the English translation of the word nymphéas ?",
    "answer": "WATERLILIES",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Rap artist and actor Marshall Mathers III is best known by his stage name Eminem but has also created an alter ego, as revealed in the titles of his 1997 EP and 1999 major label debut LP, who goes by what name?",
    "answer": "SLIM SHADY",
    "percent_correct": 89.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The Bell 101 dataset , released in 1958, was the first model of what computer device to be made commercially available, right around the time the portmanteau term for the device entered the English lexicon?",
    "answer": "MODEM",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "According to Samuel Taylor Coleridge, in what city on the sacred river Alph did Mongol ruler Kubla Khan a stately pleasure-dome decree?",
    "answer": "XANADU",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The Sunset Café, Reno Club, \"head arrangements,\" Big Joe Turner, Charlie Parker, Bennie Moten, Count Basie, and the widely imitated \"dueling tenor saxophonists\" Lester Young and Herschel Evans are all associated with the swing jazz of what city?",
    "answer": "KANSAS CITY",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "A prominent American neurosurgeon who is also a television medical correspondent may or may not be descended from monarchs who ruled much of South Asia in the fourth to sixth centuries, during what is considered the Golden Age of India. What last name do they share?",
    "answer": "GUPTA",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Kópavogur, Hafnarfjörður, Garðabær, and Mosfellsbær are among the most populous suburbs of what European capital city?",
    "answer": "REYKJAVIK",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Name the American television soap opera that premiered in March 1987 as a sister to The Young and the Restless and subsequently surpassed its older sibling to become the world's most watched soap opera (although Y&R remains #1 in the United States).",
    "answer": "THE BOLD AND THE BEAUTIFUL",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Although he did slug 563 home runs before retiring in 1987 (a total that doesn't include three famous home runs in October 1977), what Major League Baseball Hall of Famer holds the ignominious record for most career strikeouts?",
    "answer": "REGGIE JACKSON",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "The confection pictured here is known by a number of names, including one that is derived in part from a slang term for \"mouth\". What is that name? Click here",
    "answer": "GOBSTOPPER (also acc. Jawbreaker)",
    "percent_correct": 90.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "A complex triangular relationship between the title characters and a nouvelle and mercurial woman named Catherine structures the plot of what classic French New Wave film?",
    "answer": "JULES ET JIM",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "In 1960, Alan Freed, the originator of the term rock and roll , was arrested on charges of commercial bribery. His arrest and subsequent conviction were part of a series of scandals that are associated with what neologism (which is defined as an illegal undercover or indirect inducement for a commercial favor—in Freed's case, regular radio airplay)?",
    "answer": "PAYOLA",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Extending from Billy Rogers Arroyo all the way to the New Mexico border, Franklin Mountains State Park is the largest urban park in the United States, at over 24,000 acres (thirty times larger than Central Park in New York City). The park is located wholly within what Texas city?",
    "answer": "EL PASO",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "On April 27, 2014, a crowd of hundreds of thousands gathered in St. Peter's Square in Vatican City to witness Pope Francis's canonization of two former pontiffs. What were the papal names (and numbers) used by these two new saints?",
    "answer": "JOHN XXIII, JOHN PAUL II",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "The Fortune 500 annually lists the top closely held and public corporations in the United States, as ranked by gross revenue during the previous year (after adjustments). Name any one of the three companies to have sat atop the list since its inception in 1955.",
    "answer": "GENERAL MOTORS, EXXONMOBIL, WAL-MART",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Angiogenesis and intussusception are two of the three known physiological processes by which the human body creates what?",
    "answer": "BLOOD VESSELS",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The Golden Globe–winning 2010 film The Kids Are All Right is extremely similar in title—but quite different in subject matter—to a film thirty-one years earlier about whom?",
    "answer": "THE WHO",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "What is the amplitude of the cosine function shown here in green ? Click here",
    "answer": "2.5 (peak) / 5 (peak-to-peak)",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Give the musical term, from Italian, synonymous for \"from the beginning,\" and associated with Baroque arias, that instructs the performer to repeat the first section of music.",
    "answer": "DA CAPO",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The semiannual clothing trade shows in this city, which were established in 1958 and are usually held in February/March and September/October, are the third in the Big Four \"fashion weeks\" schedule, following New York and London, and preceding Paris.",
    "answer": "MILAN",
    "percent_correct": 86.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "It's been 814 weeks since this provocatively named Canadian alternative rock band has had a #1 hit on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart.",
    "answer": "BARENAKED LADIES",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Fill in the blank, from the rules of soccer (association football): \"When the whole of the ball passes over the goal line, excluding that portion between the goalposts, either in the air or on the ground, having last been played by one of the defending team, the member of the attacking team shall take a ___________.\"",
    "answer": "CORNER KICK",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "In the United States, the dessert item pictured here most often appears on menus under what Italian name? Click here",
    "answer": "ZABAGLIONE",
    "percent_correct": 18.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Name any two of the countries that are wholly within the area of the geographical region known as the Southern Cone ( Cono Sur ).",
    "answer": "ARGENTINA, CHILE, PARAGUAY, URUGUAY",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Correctly spell the word being spoken in this audio clip. The final word in the Scripps Howard National Spelling Bee in 1999, it is defined as \"excessive and often incoherent talkativeness or wordiness.\" (1 second) Click here",
    "answer": "LOGORRHEA",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "A get-rich-quick scheme by a former mid-level government official named Paul structures the plot of what classic 1842 novel, whose original primary title was The Wanderings of Chichikov ?",
    "answer": "DEAD SOULS",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "What company, founded in Tennessee in 1952 and now owned by the multinational British corporation IHG, was named after a hit 1942 musical film?",
    "answer": "HOLIDAY INN",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The stucco known as formstone , which is a common facing for urban row houses such as those pictured here, is most often associated with what eastern U.S. city (where this photograph was taken)? Click here",
    "answer": "BALTIMORE",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "With his wife, born Louisa Lane, the Irish-American actor and Philadelphia theatre manager John Drew, who died in 1862, is the progenitor of a prominent acting family that is more associated with what other name?",
    "answer": "BARRYMORE",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "With an apparent visual magnitude of 1.15, roughly equivalent to the planet Mars, the reddish giant star Pollux is the brightest star in what constellation?",
    "answer": "GEMINI",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Pictured here (cropped) is a dust jacket for a children's book authored by what comedian? Click here",
    "answer": "STEPHEN COLBERT",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "On November 4, 1922, London-born excavator Howard Carter experienced a major life event that would forever associate him most indelibly with what other individual?",
    "answer": "TUTANKHAMUN",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "The smallest number that fits the number theory definition of a perfect number is 6. What is the second-smallest perfect number?",
    "answer": "28",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are castmembers of a television series set in what city? Click here",
    "answer": "ATLANTA",
    "percent_correct": 86.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The first Sunday after the first full moon after the spring equinox is a day that is known throughout much of the world as what?",
    "answer": "EASTER/PASCH",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The world's largest river delta forms nearly half of the total area of what Asian country?",
    "answer": "BANGLADESH",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Although he has directed the spy thriller parodies OSS 117: Cairo, Nest of Spies and OSS 117: Lost in Rio , as well as the upcoming remake of the 1948 movie The Search , French director Michel Hazanavicius has received his greatest acclaim for what 2011 film?",
    "answer": "THE ARTIST",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The famous titular hero from an epic poem, written in an early Iberian romance language during the late twelfth and early thirteenth centuries, defeats the Moors during the Reconquista , regaining his glory and the faith of the Castilian king. He subsequently vanquishes evil infantes for the honor of his daughters. Name this hero.",
    "answer": "EL CID",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the German-born surrealist, Dadaist, and frottage inventor responsible for the works pictured here. Click here",
    "answer": "MAX ERNST",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The 1980s television sitcom The Hogan Family was, during its first two seasons, named after what star, who departed the series after the second-season in a well-publicized dispute with the show's producers? She was written out of the series, with Sandy Duncan stepping in as a surrogate.",
    "answer": "VALERIE HARPER",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The basic law of quantum physics that states that two electrons in an atom cannot simultaneously occupy the same quantum or energy state is an exclusion principle most commonly associated with (and named after) what Austrian physicist?",
    "answer": "WOLFGANG PAULI",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "From 1901 to 1908, the tallest building in the world was the city hall pictured here, which would remain the tallest in its city until surpassed by Liberty Place upon the latter's completion in 1987. Name the city. Click here",
    "answer": "PHILADELPHIA",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "The prestigious Edinburgh International Festival of Music and Drama, which occurs annually in August, is arguably overshadowed by an offshoot that runs concurrently and has grown to become the largest arts festival in the world. What is the name of the theatrical movement that gave its name to this alternative festival, as well as numerous subsequent others around the globe?",
    "answer": "FRINGE",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Zhang Chunqiao, Yao Wenyuan, Wang Hongwen, and Jiang Qing, who all died in prison, were members of a political faction that is today known as what?",
    "answer": "GANG OF FOUR",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "A common street food in many parts of Mexico, elote is a dish that can be served with various condiments, but is essentially what vegetable?",
    "answer": "CORN (ON THE COB)",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "A giant mock-up of a Las Vegas slot machine dominated the set of what quiz show, which was produced from the 1970s into the mid-1990s, created by Jack Barry?",
    "answer": "THE JOKER'S WILD",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This group, named after a street in the Los Angeles County community of South Gate, was the first Latino-American hip-hop group to release an album that achieved platinum status. Two of their albums reached that level in 1993: their self-titled debut, and their follow-up LP, Black Sunday . What is the group's name?",
    "answer": "CYPRESS HILL",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The ethnic group known as the Uyghur have their greatest population in what country (specifically, in a namesake autonomous region within this country)?",
    "answer": "CHINA",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Chicago community area of New City includes a neighborhood that in the early twentieth century was known as \"Packingtown\" and was the setting of what influential novel of the era?",
    "answer": "THE JUNGLE",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The Atari 2600 home video game console was released, in September 1977, with nine launch titles. Of these nine, which one was included in the box, with purchase of the system?",
    "answer": "COMBAT",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Vaslav Nijinsky, Léonide Massine, and George Balanchine were among the choreographers who worked with what Sergei Diaghilev-founded ballet company, which performed from 1909 to 1929 in countries throughout Europe and North and South America (with one ironic exception)?",
    "answer": "BALLETS RUSSES",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Known formally (and locally) as a Niezależny Samorządny Związek Zawodowy , this was the first trade union in the Eastern Bloc not controlled by the Communist Party. It is best known in English by what name?",
    "answer": "SOLIDARITY",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Around 100 million years after its formation 300 million years ago, the supercontinent Pangaea began to break apart, giving rise to two new, smaller supercontinents. Give the name of either of these, which in turn divided into the current continents of the earth.",
    "answer": "LAURASIA, GONDWANA",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The first foray into late-night programming by the nascent Fox television network occurred in 1986, with a show that would eventually be titled The Late Show and for its first eighteen months was hosted by what comic actress, comedienne, and former Tonight Show \"permanent\" guest host?",
    "answer": "JOAN RIVERS",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The self-immolation of street vendor Mohamed Bouazizi on December 17, 2010, is widely considered to mark the beginning of what came to be known throughout the world as the Arab Spring. His act took place in Sidi Bouzid, a rural town in what country?",
    "answer": "TUNISIA",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the genre of music, a successor to the frottola and the most important secular genre of sixteenth century Italy (with subsequent popularity in England), that is a song for several voices, typically with  vernacular text of an amorous nature.",
    "answer": "MADRIGAL",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Of the seven Oscar-winning acting performances directed by Woody Allen (among six actors; Dianne Wiest won twice), only one was by a man. Name that actor, who won the award in 1987 but could not receive it in person because he was busy filming Jaws: The Revenge .",
    "answer": "MICHAEL CAINE",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Name the poet and dramatist, a leading English writer during the Restoration period, whose first major work was a collection of heroic stanzas on the death of Cromwell, titled Heroic Stanzas on the Death of Cromwell . He followed this the next year with a celebration of the return of the monarchy, Astraea Redux , and in later life focused on writing plays, notably Marriage à la Mode .",
    "answer": "JOHN DRYDEN",
    "percent_correct": 12.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "London, England; Villers-sur-Mer, France; Castellón de la Plana, Spain; Stidia, Algeria; and Tema, Ghana, are among cities that share what particular distinction?",
    "answer": "PRIME MERIDIAN PASSES THROUGH",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "All Greek dramatists who are today regarded as classics were active during the time of Athenian democracy in the fourth and fifth centuries BC, and all formal performances of dramatic works at Athens during the period took place at festivals honoring what god?",
    "answer": "DIONYSUS",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The Labor Management Relations Act of 1947 , which amended 1935's National Labor Relations Act, becoming law by overcoming President Harry S Truman's veto, limits the power of labor unions and restricts the use of strikes and closed shops. The law, still in effect today, has a more common name referencing what two Republican Congressmen who sponsored it?",
    "answer": "ROBERT TAFT, FRED HARTLEY, JR.",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Of the primary financial statements used by U.S. businesses, the purpose of one is to provide detailed information about a company's assets, liabilities and shareholders' equity at a specific point in time. It is sometimes known as a statement of financial position , but is best known as what?",
    "answer": "BALANCE SHEET",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "\"I Saw Her Standing There\" by John Lennon (1981), \"Flames of Paradise\" by Jennifer Rush (1987), \"Through the Storm\" by Aretha Franklin (1989), \"Written in the Stars\" by LeAnn Rimes (1999), and \"Ghetto Gospel\" by Tupac Shakur (2005) are all singles released by the named artists in a duet with (or featuring) what other artist?",
    "answer": "ELTON JOHN",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "In May 1993, with over 50 million more people than #2 Uganda, this country became the most populous landlocked country in the world.",
    "answer": "ETHIOPIA",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "As of the weekend of March 30, 2014, what film is the top-grossing animated feature of all time, ahead of the $1.063 billion earned by Toy Story 3 (per the AMPAS definition of an \"animated feature\")?",
    "answer": "FROZEN",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The American Kennel Club classifies recognized breeds into one of seven groups, according to their primary functions and other distinctive traits. Into which group are the Bernese Mountain Dog, Boxer, Doberman Pinscher, Rottweiler, Saint Bernard, and Siberian Husky all classified?",
    "answer": "WORKING GROUP",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "In January 2013, former Deputy National Security Advisor Denis McDonough succeeded recently appointed Treasury Secretary Jack Lew in what position, which McDonough still holds today?",
    "answer": "WHITE HOUSE CHIEF OF STAFF",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Identify the modernist novel that was first published in 1922 but set on a June day eighteen years earlier and based on a work written three thousand years earlier.",
    "answer": "ULYSSES",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Debuting on a local 1950s Washington, DC, program called Sam and Friends , this enduringly popular television and film character's first network appearance was on Steve Allen's Tonight Show in 1957. He appeared regularly on television by 1969, and in the late 1970s and early 1980s he presided over what was likely the most widely viewed program in the world at the time. Name the character.",
    "answer": "KERMIT THE FROG",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "Factor the following polynomial: x 2 - 7x + 12",
    "answer": "(x-3)(x-4)",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The Battle of the Thames, which took place in 1813 in present-day Southwestern Ontario, was a defeat for the British. During the battle, which Shawnee Indian Chief was killed, essentially ending his namesake confederacy and thus the dream of an independent Indian state in the American Midwest?",
    "answer": "TECUMSEH",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The jazz musicians Bill Frisell, Kenny Burrell, Charlie Hunter, Marc Ribot, and James \"Blood\" Ulmer are all considered masters of what instrument?",
    "answer": "GUITAR",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Impoverished and increasingly desertified today, with a present population of around 50,000, this city just north of the Niger River was, along with nearby Gao, a center of commerce, scholarship, and religion in West Africa during its golden era from the twelfth through sixteenth centuries.",
    "answer": "TIMBUKTU",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Sexus is the first novel in a trilogy by American writer Henry Miller titled The Rosy Crucifixion , a fictionalized account of the author's life leading to his 1928 move to Paris. Name either of the novels that complete the trilogy.",
    "answer": "PLEXUS, NEXUS",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Who painted this? Click here",
    "answer": "PAUL GAUGUIN",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "This writer's 1762 work The Social Contract contains the famous first line \"Man is born free and everywhere he is in chains\" and also popularized the catchphrase (and later, national motto) liberté, égalité, fraternité . His earlier Julie, or the New Heloise promoted the value of family, though the author himself previously abandoned his five children to an orphanage.",
    "answer": "JEAN JACQUES ROUSSEAU",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "\"On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away\" is the official song of what U.S. state?",
    "answer": "INDIANA",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The scheduled destination of Malaysia Airlines Flight 370, which was reported lost on March 8, 2014, was the main international airport in what city?",
    "answer": "BEIJING",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What was the exact name of the category that corresponded with the color orange in the original 1981 Genus Edition of the board game Trivial Pursuit ?",
    "answer": "SPORTS & LEISURE",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The song excerpted here, which reached #22 on the Billboard Adult Contemporary chart in 1998, was the theme song to what popular comedy-drama television series? (34 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "ALLY MCBEAL",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "One legend on the etymology of this art movement's name—a precursor to surrealism, pop art, and postmodernism—says that the name was chosen at random when a knife came down in a dictionary on the French term for \"hobby horse.\"",
    "answer": "DADA",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "In 1986, this Nigerian writer and former pro-Biafran political prisoner became the first African to win the Nobel Prize in Literature.",
    "answer": "WOLE SOYINKA",
    "percent_correct": 11.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "550 foot-pounds per second, or 746 watts, equates to 1 unit of what other measurement of energy consumed per unit of time?",
    "answer": "HORSEPOWER",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "Parallel side length A plus parallel side length B multiplied by height and divided by 2. Or, (A+B)h/2: This is the mathematical formula for the area of what shape?",
    "answer": "TRAPEZOID",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Identify the woman pictured here, who is the only real-life woman ever to have been depicted on such a medium. Click here",
    "answer": "MARTHA WASHINGTON",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Among the prizes presented during the annual Cannes International Film Festival, the Caméra d'Or is awarded to the best film, as determined by the independent jury, that meets what specific criterion?",
    "answer": "FIRST FILM (FIRST FEATURE FILM BY A NEW DIRECTOR)",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the composer, likely the most celebrated musician of the late eighteenth century and often mentioned as the first of the \"great triumvirate\" of Viennese classical composers that includes Mozart and Beethoven, whose work is excerpted here. (42 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "JOSEPH HAYDN",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Identify the television program that premiered on the FX network on April 15, 2014, as a direct sequel to a 1996 Academy Award–winning film of the same name.",
    "answer": "FARGO",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The 2012 song \"Just a Fool\", whose considerable radio airplay and positive critical reception did not result in stellar chart performance, is probably most notable for being a duet by what talent show coaches?",
    "answer": "CHRISTINA AGUILERA, BLAKE SHELTON",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The October, 1469 marriage of the teenage Reyes Católicos , Isabella I and Ferdinand II, formalized the unification of what two crowns (monarchies)?",
    "answer": "CASTILE, ARAGON",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Name the German-born American actress who is well-known for her relatively infrequent but very highly regarded theatrical performances (which included originating the role of Martha in Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? on Broadway) as well as her prominence as a drama teacher, instructing at New York's HB Studios beginning in 1947 and authoring the essential Respect for Acting .",
    "answer": "UTA HAGEN",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Also known as semolina, and the preferred choice for commercially manufactured dried pasta, what is the sturdy flour type that is so named by virtue of being ground from the hardest wheat grown (which shares the name)?",
    "answer": "DURUM",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "A Mexican saying that roughly translates to \"excited\" or \"agitated\" provides the title of a 1989 novel (and subsequent film) by magic realist writer Laura Esquivel. What is this saying?",
    "answer": "LIKE WATER FOR CHOCOLATE (COMO AGUA PARA CHOCOLATE)",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Popping crease , sight screens , silly mid on , and \"Howzat?!\" are all terms from what sport?",
    "answer": "CRICKET",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "France's self-governing territorial collectivité d'outre-mer Saint Pierre and Miquelon sits more than 2,700 miles (4,400 km) from Paris, but just 16 miles (26 km) off the coast of what other country?",
    "answer": "CANADA",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are buildings designed by what renowned American architect? Click here",
    "answer": "RICHARD MEIER",
    "percent_correct": 8.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "\"When our Lord and Master, Jesus Christ, said 'Repent,' He called for the entire life of believers to be one of repentance.\" \"And let them thus be more confident of entering heaven through many tribulations rather than through a false assurance of peace.\" These two quotations are English translations of the first and ninety-fifth (and final) items on a list most associated with what man?",
    "answer": "MARTIN LUTHER",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The fictional Ohio-based department store Winfred-Lauder is the workplace of the title character from what television sitcom?",
    "answer": "THE DREW CAREY SHOW",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "One of the most famous featured appearances of the piccolo in the history of music is in Thé (Danse chinoise) , which occurs during the second act of what ballet?",
    "answer": "THE NUTCRACKER",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Back into Hell and The Monster Is Loose are subtitles of albums (from 1993 and 2006, respectively) that are the second and third of a trilogy that began in 1977. What is the stage name of the recording artist who released these albums?",
    "answer": "MEAT LOAF",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In chemistry, any organic compound in which a covalently bonded oxygen and hydrogen atom group (\"hydroxyl,\" -OH) is bound to a carbon atom is classified as what term?",
    "answer": "ALCOHOL",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The U.S. Supreme Court voted 5-4  in the 1895 case Pollock v. Farmers' Loan & Trust Co. to strike down a federal act from the previous year, by declaring what unconstitutional? (Eighteen years later, the vote would be superseded by a constitutional amendment.)",
    "answer": "INCOME TAX",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Name the fruit, uncommon in the United States until the 1950s, that was originally known as the Chinese gooseberry but was renamed by exporters to avoid confusion with the unrelated green gooseberry (and to reference the fruit's geographic association).",
    "answer": "KIWIFRUIT",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "The thoroughly modern Millie Dillmount, the goes-for-anything Reno Sweeney, and the drowsily chaperoned Janet Van De Graaff are among the Broadway roles performed by what Tony-winning actress?",
    "answer": "SUTTON FOSTER",
    "percent_correct": 18.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The term bolshevik is derived from the Russian word for \"majority.\" What is the historically contemporaneous term derived from the Russian for \"minority\"?",
    "answer": "MENSHEVIK",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Fill in the missing item from this properly ordered list of names: Clarkson, Studdard, Barrino, ______________, Hicks.",
    "answer": "UNDERWOOD",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The Buffalo Braves, one of three National Basketball Association expansion franchises that began play in the 1970–71 season, moved to San Diego in 1978 and took on what new nickname?",
    "answer": "CLIPPERS",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The text in this image is written in what language? Click here",
    "answer": "BASQUE",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Legendary pre-WWII harmonica player DeFord Bailey was the first African-American to join the Grand Ole Opry, and in 1993 Charley Pride became the second. Name the man, a Grammy-winning and multi-platinum former rock-and-roller, who in 2012 was invited to become the third.",
    "answer": "DARIUS RUCKER",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "British psychiatrist Lionel Penrose and his mathematician son, Roger, conceived a structure known as the Penrose triangle, and subsequently the Penrose stairs, which both influenced and were influenced by the work of what twentieth-century artist?",
    "answer": "M.C. ESCHER",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Identify this gentleman. Click here",
    "answer": "HOWARD SCHULTZ",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Despite having only the ninth-most miles of coastline (per the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration), which U.S. state has the most lighthouses? In part, this is due to 100% of its coastline being different in nature from any other top-eighteen coastline state?",
    "answer": "MICHIGAN",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Although she was not involved in their creation, garments such as the one pictured here are most associated with what nineteenth-century American journalist and women's rights advocate? Click here",
    "answer": "AMELIA BLOOMER",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Of the eight planets in the solar system, identify those that do not have moons.",
    "answer": "MERCURY, VENUS",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Name any one of the four card categories used in the original version of the popular board game Cranium .",
    "answer": "CREATIVE CAT, DATA HEAD, WORD WORM, STAR PERFORMER",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL61",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Although the implement pictured here has a number of potential kitchen uses, it is manufactured expressly for use with what food item? Click here",
    "answer": "AVOCADO",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "While the Latin American Christmas treat mazapán is often made with peanuts, the confection known commonly as marzipan typically consists of paste made from the drupe of what tree?",
    "answer": "ALMOND",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "\"John Goes-Everywhere\" (or idiomatically, \"John Skeleton Key\") would be the English translation of the name of Phileas Fogg's valet in Around the World in Eighty Days . What was the valet's name?",
    "answer": "JEAN PASSEPARTOUT",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Suture joints are a specific type of connective tissue found in the human body in what anatomical structure?",
    "answer": "CRANIUM/SKULL",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Give the name of the border crossing (and nearby city) highlighted in this image. Click here",
    "answer": "RAFAH",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Graubünden, Valais, and Ticino are among the major administrative divisions of what nation?",
    "answer": "SWITZERLAND",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Native speakers of Latin in ancient Rome used what letter to express the number quingenti ?",
    "answer": "D",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Lord Byng of Vimy (Julian Hedworth George Byng, 1st Viscount Byng of Vimy -- a.k.a. \"Bungo\"), served from 1921 to 1926 as Governor General of what British Dominion?",
    "answer": "CANADA",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What book, first published in 1653, remains today almost surely the most celebrated work of literature on the vitality and artistry of fly fishing (while living a life of pleasant serenity)?",
    "answer": "THE COMPLEAT ANGLER",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "A musical march known as a screamer , such as those written by famous screamer composer Karl L. King, is most closely associated with what type of event?",
    "answer": "CIRCUS",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the woman in this image (last name not required). Click here",
    "answer": "CHRISTINA (ANNA CHRISTINA OLSON)",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "These comedic theatre legends first appeared together on stage in 1924, in Ferenc Molnár's The Guardsman , two years after their marriage, and had their swan song in 1958's The Visit , in the Broadway theatre renamed in their honor. Name these stage stars.",
    "answer": "ALFRED LUNT, LYNN FONTANNE",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Yo dawg, TLC's Overhaulin' , CMT's Trick My Truck , Speed Channel's Unique Whips , and Spike TV's Ride with Funkmaster Flex were all thematically similar to what MTV hit series, which premiered in March, 2004?",
    "answer": "PIMP MY RIDE",
    "percent_correct": 91.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "James B. Beam, Edmund Haynes Taylor, Jr., Albert B. Blanton, and James E. Pepper were famous American bourbon whiskey distillers who were all formally bestowed, by an act of government, with what honorific title?",
    "answer": "COLONEL",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Although John Denver associates it with West Virginia in \"Take Me Home, Country Roads\", this tributary of the Potomac only runs through the state for approximately 20 miles, while the vast majority of the river and its major forks are in Virginia. Name the river.",
    "answer": "SHENANDOAH",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "While \"Boom Clap\" became her first Billboard top ten single as a solo artist, what British singer and songwriter had already achieved significant popularity as a co-writer and featured artist on the hit songs \"I Love It\" by Icona Pop and \"Fancy\" by Iggy Azalea?",
    "answer": "CHARLI XCX",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "\"Universal donors\" is a term (not strictly accurate) used to refer to individuals who are classified by what blood type (in the most common blood group system, including Rh factor)?",
    "answer": "TYPE O NEGATIVE",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Mary, Eliza, Julia, Lucy, Lucretia, Mary (a different one), Rose, Frances, Caroline, Frances (the same one), and Ida were names of women among those who served during the second half of the 19th century in what exclusive position?",
    "answer": "FIRST LADY OF THE UNITED STATES",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Both the youngest and the oldest winners of college football's Heisman Trophy award did so while playing for what university?",
    "answer": "FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "This island was first explored by the Portuguese in the 16th century, controlled by the French in the 18th century, and granted independence from the British in 1968, but it was the Dutch who initially settled the island, named it, and killed all the dodos.",
    "answer": "MAURITIUS",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "A former vassal defeated rival commanders in 1600 and established a shogunate that initiated a period of two and a half centuries of internal stability in Japan. What was the name of this shogun (and his namesake shogunate)?",
    "answer": "TOKUGAWA IEYASU",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "This multi-talented Broadway star is the only person to win Tony Awards in the same categories in consecutive years  (Best Choreography and Best Direction of a Musical in 1990-91, for Grand Hotel and The Will Rogers Follies ), and the first to win in four different categories (the aforementioned plus featured actor and leading actor).",
    "answer": "TOMMY TUNE",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Robert \"Rosebud\" Butt, a bartender at the Oak Beach Inn in Suffolk County, New York, near Jones Beach, is credited with inventing what alcoholic drink, during a contest to create a new mixed drink which includes Triple Sec?",
    "answer": "LONG ISLAND ICED TEA",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "\"Come with me if you want to live\" is a famous line, probably the second-most famous line (certainly not the first), from what 1984 film?",
    "answer": "THE TERMINATOR",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Uncas, also referrred to as Le Cerf Agile , is the title character of what historical novel from 1826?",
    "answer": "THE LAST OF THE MOHICANS",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The name of China's capital city, Beijing (romanized as Peking), literally means \"northern capital\". What other Chinese city's name is literally \"southern capital\"?",
    "answer": "NANJING/NANKING",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Among the accords in the 1995 Dayton Agreement was the establishment of the Republika Srpska as a formal political entity within what country?",
    "answer": "BOSNIA AND HERZEGOVINA",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Shelley Duvall's Faerie Tale Theatre was, in 1982, this television network's first original series, though it made bigger news the following year by becoming the first cable network to produce new episodes of a cancelled broadcast network series (the former CBS series The Paper Chase ). Name this network.",
    "answer": "SHOWTIME",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The squares of the periods of revolution of all planets are proportional to the cubes of their mean distances from the sun. This is taken from 1619's Harmonices mundi , by whom?",
    "answer": "JOHANNES KEPLER",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This term, the opposite of staccato , directs a musician to perform a given musical passage in a smooth and connected manner, with no break between the notes.",
    "answer": "LEGATO",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "JTBC Founders Cup, Kraft Nabisco Championship, Portland Classic, Marathon Classic, Mizuno Classic: These are all events run by what American sports organization?",
    "answer": "LADIES PROFESSIONAL GOLF ASSOCIATION (LPGA)",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the company that manufactured the guitars being played in this montage. Click here",
    "answer": "FENDER",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Although the official count is now closer to 500, this European capital city has retained the nickname \"City of 100 Spires\" based on an 18th century count by local philosopher and mathematician Bernhard Bolzano. Included in both counts are the spires of the Gothic St. Vitus, St. Wenceslas and St. Adalbert Cathedral.",
    "answer": "PRAGUE",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the architect and engineer most responsible for the design in this edited image. Click here",
    "answer": "PIERRE L'ENFANT",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "Fill in the blank in this ordered list: mega, giga, tera, _________, exa, zetta, yotta.",
    "answer": "PETA",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Despite having played before the introduction of the three-point line, and before freshmen were eligible to play varsity, this former LSU Tiger remains the all-time leading scorer in NCAA Division I men's basketball history (and it's not even really very close).",
    "answer": "PETE MARAVICH",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Actor Tom Hanks has been featured in starring roles in six films with titles that are exactly one word (and one word only). Name any four of these six films.",
    "answer": "SPLASH, VOLUNTEERS, DRAGNET, BIG, PUNCHLINE, PHILADELPHIA",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "A particular type of art known as scrimshaw is distinctive for its use of what medium?",
    "answer": "BONE/IVORY",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The French population in what country dropped from around 1 million in 1954 to below 100,000 by 1966, four years after the country’'s foundational Evian Accords were signed?",
    "answer": "ALGERIA",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "A New York gangster (who, unrelatedly, looks very similar to Tony Soprano's consigliere) is placed in the Federal Witness Protection Program and sent to start a new life in Norway in what currently running television series?",
    "answer": "LILYHAMMER",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Nemean Lion, Hydra, Erymanthian Boar, and Stymphalian Birds are among a dozen items associated most closely with whom?",
    "answer": "HERACLES/HERCULES",
    "percent_correct": 78.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The type of crab pictured here is most often referred to by what name? Click here",
    "answer": "FIDDLER CRAB",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Modern linguistics typically designates six living languages as within the language classification known as Celtic languages , all six of which are (or were) spoken in far northwest Europe. Name any two of these six.",
    "answer": "BRETON, CORNISH, IRISH, MANX, SCOTTISH GAELIC (GAELIC), WELSH",
    "percent_correct": 84.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Give the four words that complete this line from the Holy Bible, Leviticus 20:24: Hence I have said to you, You are to possess their land, and I Myself will give it to you to possess it, a land flowing  ____________.",
    "answer": "WITH MILK AND HONEY",
    "percent_correct": 86.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "According to legend, a noteworthy oxcart's yoke was joined to the pole of a wagon, sitting on the acropolis of the capital city of ancient Phrygia in Asia Minor, by way of a device which is known today as what?",
    "answer": "GORDIAN KNOT",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Chuck Wepner, who was known during his heyday as the \"Bayonne Bleeder,\" provided inspiration for what iconic and enduring film character?",
    "answer": "ROCKY BALBOA",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "This term, used in figure skating for the element pictured here, and common in construction (and particularly bridge construction), is a beam or girder with fixed support at only one end. Click here",
    "answer": "CANTILEVER",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Provide the one item missing from this otherwise complete set: New South Wales, Queensland, South Australia, Victoria, Western Australia.",
    "answer": "TASMANIA",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Although it can vary depending on location, by tradition authentic caviar is roe from specific Black Sea or Caspian Sea species of what type of fish?",
    "answer": "STURGEON",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Jason and the Argonauts would have never taken the Golden Fleece without the help of what woman, whose later filicidal ways were dramatized by Euripides?",
    "answer": "MEDEA",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "\"Who Loves You\" and \"December, 1963 (Oh, What a Night)\" were major hits in 1975 for what musical group? They were band's first hits in seven years, and also their last.",
    "answer": "THE FOUR SEASONS",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "In 17 of the 50 U.S. states, the state's capital city is also its most populous municipality. At the other end, in eight states, the capital city is not in the state's top 10 most populous municipalities. Name any one of these eight states.",
    "answer": "KY, MD, MO, NV, NY, PA, VT, WA",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "What major American university was founded in 1890 on land donated by retail magnate and philanthropist Marshall Field?",
    "answer": "UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Once a major industry, before the advent of jet air travel, transatlantic service via ocean liner is today served by only one vessel, the flagship of the Cunard Line. What is her full name?",
    "answer": "QUEEN MARY 2",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "David Scott, John W. Young, Edgar Mitchell, James Irwin, and Harrison Schmitt are among the lesser known of the exactly 12 men (so far) who have done what?",
    "answer": "WALKED ON THE MOON",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Mysterious spies are attempting to smuggle microfilm containing government secrets out of the country. They try to kill George Kaplan, an agent who is on their trail, but are unsuccessful. The man they're trying to kill isn't even Kaplan -- in fact, Kaplan doesn't actually exist. This is the basis of the plot of what 1959 spy thriller?",
    "answer": "NORTH BY NORTHWEST",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This painting, controversial in its day, is the work of what French painter? Click here",
    "answer": "EDOUARD MANET",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The medical institutions Cook County General Hospital, Seattle Grace Mercy West Hospital, Princeton-Plainsboro Teaching Hospital, and New York's All Saints Hospital all most notably have what in common?",
    "answer": "FICTIONAL HOSPITALS (ON TELEVISION)",
    "percent_correct": 88.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the composer of this piece of music. Click here",
    "answer": "MODEST MUSSORGSKY",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The discovery of the law of conservation of mass, as well as the discovery of the elements oxygen and hydrogen, are among the reasons that this Frenchman is considered the \"Father of Modern Chemistry.\"",
    "answer": "ANTOINE LAVOISIER",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What word, known in a culinary context, is the cognate of a term from the Tupí language of South America for a process by which starch of the cassava plant is made edible?",
    "answer": "TAPIOCA",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "In the fourth century BC, the city of Rome was enclosed within a wall and consisted of seven hills. Name any two of these seven hills of Rome.",
    "answer": "AVENTINE, CAELIAN, CAPITOLINE, ESQUILINE, PALATINE, QUIRINAL, VIMINAL",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Identify the actor on the left in this photo from 1921. Click here",
    "answer": "RUDOLPH VALENTINO",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The first modern-day non-royal female head of state in the Western Hemisphere took office in July 1974, becoming president upon the death of her husband Juan. What was her name (first and last required)?",
    "answer": "ISABEL PERÓN",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The first launch of a rocket into space was done by Germany in 1942 (the V-2), but the first rocket to carry a payload into space was a modified R-7 Semyorka, launched by Russia. What was the name of its payload (as well as a name given to the rocket itself)?",
    "answer": "SPUTNIK (SPUTNIK 1)",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The commemoratively named Ali Mall, named after Muhammad Ali and constructed in late 1975, is located next to the Araneta Coliseum in what city (where the mall was the city's first major shopping mall)?",
    "answer": "QUEZON CITY/MANILA",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "This author's first published novel was published in 1984 by the Naval Institute Press (the film would follow six years later), but became a bestseller (his first of 17) after praise from President Ronald Reagan. Name the author.",
    "answer": "TOM CLANCY",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "This term's original Greek meaning is \"a man who has a particular skill or claim to wisdom.\" By the fifth century BC, it became a term applied to itinerant teachers who traveled from city to city providing private instruction and lectures for a fee. More negatively, today it can refer to a specious or captious reasoner. What is the term?",
    "answer": "SOPHIST",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "A flamboyant frontman for a rock band from the 70s and 80s, a 1986 hit song by Bananarama, a 1995 song by Michael Jackson, a guitarist for the heavy metal band Mötley Crüe, and a Grammy-winning 2001 song from Train—their names have what in common?",
    "answer": "PLANETS",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "These two oil brands, which are named after the location of the first oil boom in the United States, were independent companies that merged in 1998 before being acquired by the Royal Dutch/Shell Group four years later. Name these two automotive motor oil brands.",
    "answer": "PENNZOIL, QUAKER STATE",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Which relatively rare and extremely dense chemical element has the highest melting point (at standard pressure)?",
    "answer": "TUNGSTEN",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The animal here shares its common name with a term for a Southern sympathizer in the North during the U.S. Civil War (specifically, a member of a group of Democrats who supported an immediate peace settlement and cessation of military coercion of the Confederacy). What is this term? Click here",
    "answer": "COPPERHEAD",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "What are these titular flowers? Click here",
    "answer": "IRISES",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This American rock band's greatest hits compilation album from 1976 was the first to receive official platinum recognition from the RIAA for one million shipments in the United States (the award was introduced that year). Today, with Michael Jackson's Thriller , it is considered the all-time top-selling album in the United States (and third worldwide). Name the band.",
    "answer": "EAGLES",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "In mathematics, vectors are quantities that express both magnitude and direction, such as velocity and force. What is the parallel term, from Latin for ladder , for quantities of only one dimension (magnitude), such as speed or mass?",
    "answer": "SCALAR",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Published in 1902, The Little White Bird; Or, Adventures in Kensington Gardens introduced the mythology of what reckless and boastful juvenile character?",
    "answer": "PETER PAN",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The musical instrument known as the concertina is most similar to what other, much better known instrument, in both operation and appearance, even though there are distinct differences between the two instruments?",
    "answer": "ACCORDION",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the technical , Greek-derived name for the device in this photograph? Click here",
    "answer": "SPHYGMOMANOMETER",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "As indicated in its logo, the Ohio Art Company, based in the small city of Bryan, is best known for its development and marketing of what well-known toy?",
    "answer": "ETCH A SKETCH",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The change in internal energy of a system is equal to the heat supplied to the system, minus the work done by the system . Or, ΔU=Q-W . These are expressions of a law of physics, a version of the law of conservation of energy, which is most commonly known as what?",
    "answer": "FIRST LAW OF THERMODYNAMICS",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "The paintings in this montage all currently hang near, and are associated with (though are not necessarily of ), what river? Click here",
    "answer": "HUDSON",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "After the firing of the show's creator John Kricfalusi in 1992, Billy West took over voicing duties for both title characters in what animated television series?",
    "answer": "THE REN & STIMPY SHOW",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Western Michigan native Julie Krone is noteworthy as the first woman ever inducted into the primary American hall of fame associated with what sport?",
    "answer": "HORSE RACING",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "British Honduras was the colonial name of what current country, which, because of its Anglophone legacy, is the only country in Central America with English as its official language?",
    "answer": "BELIZE",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "This organization, which was established in 1971 as an evolution of the informal Democratic Select Committee, has grown from its original 12 members to over 40 today, including its current Chair, U.S. Representative Marcia Fudge of Cleveland, Ohio.",
    "answer": "CONGRESSIONAL BLACK CAUCUS",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "What artist received the Oscar for Best Original Song of 2002, for \"Lose Yourself,\" the first rap song to be so accorded by the Academy?",
    "answer": "EMINEM",
    "percent_correct": 89.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In addition to its namesake, the multinational clothing and accessories retailer Gap Inc. owns five other major retail brands (not including Gap variations such as Baby Gap). Name any three of these brands.",
    "answer": "BANANA REPUBLIC, OLD NAVY, PIPERLIME, ATHLETA, INTERMIX",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "On August 21, 2014, four firefighters in Campbellsville, Kentucky, were injured when electricity raced from a high-voltage line to the bucket of an aerial ladder truck in which they were standing. What popular activity were the men participating in?",
    "answer": "ICE BUCKET CHALLENGE",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "English translations of this novella often render a word in its famous first line as \"insect,\" \"bug,\" or \"beetle,\" though the word ( Ungeziefer ) translates literally to \"vermin\".",
    "answer": "THE METAMORPHOSIS",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Possibly the biggest news event of 1453 (insofar as \"news\" existed at the time) was the fall in late May of what city? It spelled the end of one centuries-old empire, and marked the rise of another.",
    "answer": "CONSTANTINOPLE",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The man in this lightly edited photograph is the head of what organization? Click here",
    "answer": "FIFA",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "In this film's famous example of a film-editing technique known as match cut , a spinning bone cuts to a compositionally matching nuclear weapons satellite. What is the name of the film?",
    "answer": "2001: A SPACE ODYSSEY",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "What is the occupation of Escamillo, the lover of the title character in Carmen who fights the murderous Don José in the opera's third act?",
    "answer": "TOREADOR (BULLFIGHTER)",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In 1901, the theory that yellow fever is transmitted by a species of mosquito was confirmed (and its transmission through direct contact disproven) by a team led by what physician? For this and other reasons, he is very possibly history's most recognizable U.S. Army physician, by name.",
    "answer": "WALTER REED",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "There is one word redacted in this image. What is that word? Click here",
    "answer": "SUCCOTASH",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The ill-fated invasion of England led by the Spanish Armada in 1588 was precipitated, in large part, by the execution one year earlier of what rival to the English throne (held at the time by Elizabeth I)?",
    "answer": "MARY, QUEEN OF SCOTS",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Identify this man. Click here",
    "answer": "BERNARD SHAW",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "David and Goliath: Underdogs, Misfits, and the Art of Battling Giants is the fifth New York Times best seller from what Canadian journalist and The New Yorker staff writer?",
    "answer": "MALCOLM GLADWELL",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Until King Louis XIV moved his main residence to the Palace of Versailles in 1682, this Parisian landmark was the monarch's official residence, having been enlarged over the years, integrated with the adjacent Tuileries Palace, and enhanced with an elaborately planned garden.",
    "answer": "LOUVRE PALACE",
    "percent_correct": 65.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "In geometry, two angles that add up to 90 degrees are said to be complementary . What is the term for angles that add up to 180 degrees?",
    "answer": "SUPPLEMENTARY",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "On two occasions in the late 13th century, attacks on Japan by Kublai Khan's armies were thwarted with the help of typhoons which the Japanese regarded as \"divine winds.\" What was the Japanese term used for these typhoons? This term became common many years later in a different context.",
    "answer": "KAMIKAZE",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Give the name for the branch of metaphysics that studies being, the nature of reality, and the establishment of what is . It is a compound term derived from the Greek words for \"being\" and \"science\" or \"knowledge\".",
    "answer": "ONTOLOGY",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Fill in the blank in this excerpt from section 8.05 of the Major League Baseball Official Rules (2014 Edition): If there is a runner, or runners, it is a _________ when -- (a) The pitcher, while touching his plate, makes any motion naturally associated with his pitch and fails to make such delivery;",
    "answer": "BALK",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What is the notable distinction shared by Africa's Lake Volta, Lake Kariba, and Lake Nasser? They are three of the four largest in the world, by volume, among those that share this distinction.",
    "answer": "MAN-MADE",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "In history, there is exactly one person who has been referred to in an official manner as Bundeskanzlerin . Name that person.",
    "answer": "ANGELA MERKEL",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In botany, abscission is the process through which a plant loses all its leaves for a part of the year. What is the botanical term, from Latin for \"fall off,\" for the type of plant that goes through abscission?",
    "answer": "DECIDUOUS",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "What the fuck is the name of the fucking successful playwright whose early off-Broadway plays include The Duck Variations , Sexual Perversity in Chicago , and American fucking Buffalo ?",
    "answer": "DAVID FUCKING MAMET",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Tenochtitlan was the largest and most important altepetl of what Mesoamerican people?",
    "answer": "AZTEC",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "1989's City of Sadness was the first internationally acclaimed feature film from what country after its lifting of martial law two years prior? Shortly thereafter, the \"Father Knows Best\" trilogy, which consisted of Pushing Hands , The Wedding Banquet , and Eat Drink Man Woman , brought greater attention to the nation's cinema.",
    "answer": "REPUBLIC OF CHINA/TAIWAN",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The Grammy-winning contemporary bluegrass trio Nickel Creek are protégés of what other successful bluegrass-country artist, who produced the band's first two major-label albums?",
    "answer": "ALISON KRAUSS",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In the People's Republic of China, the yuan is the basic unit of the official currency, which is known by what name (meaning literally \"people's currency\")?",
    "answer": "RENMINBI",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The Tenure of Office Act, a politically driven federal law that was ultimately declared unconstitutional by the U.S. Supreme Court, provided that federal office-holders whose appointment required Senate confirmation could not be removed without the approval of the Senate. The battles over its passage and enforcement were dominant factors (perhaps the dominant factors) in the largely unsuccessful term of what U.S. president?",
    "answer": "ANDREW JOHNSON",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The 1927 Greta Garbo film Love is an adaptation of what classic 1877 novel? The film has a wildly alternative ending for American audiences: Garbo's character is reunited with her cavalry officer lover in the end and never throws herself under the carriage of a passing train at Obiralovka.",
    "answer": "ANNA KARENINA",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "This southern province of Thailand, which consists of the country's largest island and is a major tourist destination, made international news in late 2004 due to devastation caused by the Indian Ocean earthquake and subsequent tsunami.",
    "answer": "PHUKET",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "In 1994, at age 29, this journalist (and future television host and talent competition judge) was appointed editor of the newspaper News of the World by Rupert Murdoch, becoming the UK's youngest national newspaper editor in over 50 years.",
    "answer": "PIERS MORGAN",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "La Marzocco, Rancilio, Nuova Simonelli, and La Spaziale are among the leading manufacturers of machines used to produce what?",
    "answer": "ESPRESSO",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In mammals, the skeleton of what organ is formed by nine cartilages, including the thyroid cartilage, the arytenoid cartilages, and the epiglottis?",
    "answer": "LARYNX",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In standard elite competitions of artistic gymnastics, men compete on six events, whereas women compete on four. Which two events/apparatus are shared by both men and women (i.e., components of both competitions)?",
    "answer": "FLOOR EXERCISE, VAULT",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "A literary collection known as the Lunyu , believed to have been written during what is now known as the Warring States period, is a compilation of analects by whom?",
    "answer": "CONFUCIUS",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "This temple, built in the 12th century by King Suryavarman II as a dedication to the Hindu god Vishnu, remains the largest religious building in the world.",
    "answer": "ANGKOR WAT",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The video for the song excerpted here, a remake of a 1966 hit by The Young Rascals, was the second ever broadcast on MTV on August 1, 1981. Identify the song. (16 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "YOU BETTER RUN",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Identify the American architect and \"father of skyscrapers\" who, with his partner Dankmar Adler, is responsible for the buildings pictured here. Click here",
    "answer": "LOUIS SULLIVAN",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Nadine Gordimer, J.M. Coetzee, Athol Fugard, Breyten Breytenbach, and Bessie Head are all writers who were born in what country?",
    "answer": "SOUTH AFRICA",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are two future athletes in what Olympic event? Click here",
    "answer": "DECATHLON",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Between the first four \"Rightly Guided\" caliphs of the Rashidun Caliphate in the 7th century and the Ottoman Caliphate of 1517-1924, there were two other major Islamic caliphates, which ruled from 661 to 750 and from 750 to 1517. Give the most common name of either of the two.",
    "answer": "UMAYYAD, ABBASID",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "W.A. Mozart's Serenade No. 13 for Strings in G Major , which was composed in 1787, is better known by what title (though it's believed that this was not Mozart's intentional title, but rather a notation for his records)?",
    "answer": "EINE KLEINE NACHTMUSIK",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are characters from what television series? Click here",
    "answer": "ORPHAN BLACK",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Who painted this? Click here",
    "answer": "EDWARD HOPPER",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What English word, whose first usage is believed to be in the early 18th century (and definitely cannot be before 1605), is an adjective defined as \"extravagantly chivalrous or romantic, and foolishly impractical\"?",
    "answer": "QUIXOTIC",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The Jacquard system, devised by and named after French engineer Joseph Jacquard, is the use of a series of punched cards to direct the operation of what type of machine?",
    "answer": "LOOM",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The first major land battle of the 1904 Russo-Japanese War was fought near (and is named after) the Yalu River, which today forms part of the border between what two nations?",
    "answer": "CHINA, NORTH KOREA",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "In this Shakespeare play, only Albany, Edgar, and Kent walk off the stage at the end of the long and relentlessly depressing final scene (with Kent predicting his imminent demise). Everyone else is dead.",
    "answer": "KING LEAR",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "On the A&E network, this television series's fourth season premiere, which aired on August 14, 2013, drew 11.8 million viewers, making it the most-watched nonfiction cable series episode in television history.",
    "answer": "DUCK DYNASTY",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Ambassador Organics is a brand of organic food products founded by what pioneering former U.S. senator, U.S. ambassador, and unsuccessful Chicago mayoral candidate?",
    "answer": "CAROL MOSELEY BRAUN",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Joseph Nicéphore Niépce, William Henry Fox Talbot, Sir John F.W. Herschel, Eadweard Muybridge, and Edwin H. Land are all important figures in the history of what field of art?",
    "answer": "PHOTOGRAPHY",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "This is a screen capture from what website? Click here",
    "answer": "TWITCH",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The Battle of Santa Clara, which occurred in December 1958, was a decisive and final victory for Cuban revolutionaries, resulting in the overthrow of Fulgencio Batista and ascension of Fidel Castro. Name the military leader who commanded the victorious rebel forces in the Battle of Santa Clara.",
    "answer": "CHE GUEVARA",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Alan Ritchson, Noel Fisher, Pete Ploszek, and Jeremy Howard play the title characters in what 2014 big-budget Hollywood blockbuster?",
    "answer": "TEENAGE MUTANT NINJA TURTLES",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What are the first names of the characters on the American comedy television show The Office whose wedding drives the plot in the series finale, which aired in May 2013?",
    "answer": "DWIGHT, ANGELA",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Provide the name missing from this otherwise complete list: Niall Horan, Zayn Malik, Liam Payne, Louis Tomlinson, ________.",
    "answer": "HARRY STYLES",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What base unit of measurement is now defined, per the standard International System of Units (SI), as the duration of 9,192,631,770 cycles of regulation of the cesium-133 isotope?",
    "answer": "SECOND",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "What is the determinant of the matrix in this image? Click here",
    "answer": "FIVE",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Córdoba, Rosario, Mendoza, and Tucumán are the second through fifth largest cities, by population, in what South American nation?",
    "answer": "ARGENTINA",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What is the word, meaning \"dry\" or \"unrefined\" in French, that is used to describe champagne that is dry in style, with very low levels of sugar in the bottle?",
    "answer": "BRUT (also SEC)",
    "percent_correct": 84.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Although it is a mostly forgettable box-office flop, the 1997 film Father's Day is notable today for being the only feature film in which what two comedians and close friends appear on screen together?",
    "answer": "BILLY CRYSTAL, ROBIN WILLIAMS",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Upon its release, this 1948 Vittorio De Sica film received criticism domestically because of its negative depiction of Italians. Nevertheless, it is widely regarded as one of the greatest films of all time and certainly the masterpiece of the Italian Neorealism movement. What is the film?",
    "answer": "BICYCLE THIEVES (THE BICYCLE THIEF/LADRI DI BICICLETTE)",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Within two years after the formation of the Commonwealth of Independent States, which was created just before the dissolution of the Soviet Union in December 1991, all but three of the former Soviet Republics were participating in the Commonwealth. Name any two of these three.",
    "answer": "ESTONIA, LATVIA, LITHUANIA",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Name the Toronto-based publishing company that commands the market for romance novels sold in North America (releasing over 1,000 titles per year). Because of its domination of the market by the 1970s, the name of the company itself became synonymous with the genre.",
    "answer": "HARLEQUIN ENTERPRISES",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "This polymeric carbohydrate has the formula (C 6 H 10 O 5 ) n , is believed to be the most common organic compound in the earth's terrestrial environment, and has a multitude of practical uses. What is it best known as?",
    "answer": "CELLULOSE",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The WTA (Women's Tennis Association), founded by Billie Jean King, governs the major worldwide tour and ranking system for women's professional tennis. What is the three-letter abbreviation for the men's equivalent?",
    "answer": "ATP",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL62",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "An episode titled \"Chuckles Bites the Dust,\" whose plot centered on the death of a clown, and which is widely considered one of the greatest episodes in sitcom history, is from the 1975–76 season of what classic television series?",
    "answer": "THE MARY TYLER MOORE SHOW",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "While the Supreme Leader of Iran (since 1989, Ali Khamenei) is the nation's head of state, the highest popularly elected official is President. Identify the current President of Iran, who succeeded Mahmoud Ahmadinejad in August, 2013.",
    "answer": "HASSAN ROUHANI",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "In addition to being a named party in the historic U.S. Supreme Court case Roe v. Wade , long-time Dallas District Attorney Henry M. Wade also famously led the 1964 prosecution of whom?",
    "answer": "JACK RUBY",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The 1921 Ryūnosuke Akutagawa short story \"Yabu no Naka\" (\"In the Grove\"), in which several characters relate mutually contradictory versions of a rape and murder, supplied the plot to what celebrated Akira Kurosawa film—whose title is taken, incidentally, from that of a different Akutagawa story?",
    "answer": "RASHŌMON",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Name the aniseed-flavored liqueur native to southern France, similar to Pernod in the north, whose name comes from a local dialect for \"mixed\" or \"confused,\" and which is no longer produced with any of the absinthe that made it most distinctive.",
    "answer": "PASTIS",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The Keck 1 and Keck 2, Hobby-Eberly, Subaru, and GranTeCan are among the world's largest what?",
    "answer": "TELESCOPE",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The book, culture, and current affairs journal abbreviated TLS is produced weekly by British-based newspaper publisher News UK, in cooperation with one of the company's main London dailies (but not as a part of it since 1914, despite the journal's name). What do the letters TLS stand for?",
    "answer": "TIMES LITERARY SUPPLEMENT",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the only child of the actress ( not character ) highlighted with the red circle in this cast photograph. Click here",
    "answer": "LENNY KRAVITZ",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Franz Liszt's Transcendental compositions and Frédéric Chopin's collections numbered Opus 10 and 25 are among the better known (and more often performed) examples of what musical form, whose name indicates its primary purpose as practice material?",
    "answer": "ÉTUDE",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The period of geological time from 1.64 million years ago to today is known as the Quaternary Period , and is itself divided into two epochs: the Pleistocene (1.64 million to 10,000 years ago), and what other, which continues through to the present?",
    "answer": "HOLOCENE",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What city is this? Click here",
    "answer": "LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "What was the occupation shared by Philadelphians David Hayes Agnew and Samuel D. Gross, while they were subjects of famous 19th century paintings by American artist Thomas Eakins?",
    "answer": "PHYSICIAN/SURGEON",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "What number is the geometric mean of 4 and 9?",
    "answer": "SIX",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "A failed coup d'etat (or putsch ) led by Adolf Hitler in November, 1923, in Munich, led to the banning of the Nazi Party and his 264-day encarceration at Landsberg Prison, where he wrote Mein Kampf . This unsuccessful overthrow is known today by a name which references the type of business where it was launched—what is that type of business?",
    "answer": "BEER HALL",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The three main stars of the 1979 film The China Syndrome all won Academy Awards for leading roles in other films, four times among the three. Name any one of these four other films ( not actors).",
    "answer": "KLUTE, SAVE THE TIGER, COMING HOME, WALL STREET",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The uniform number of basketball Hall-of-Famer David Robinson, when expressed in hexadecimal, becomes the uniform number of basketball Hall-of-Famer Magic Johnson. Please provide both numbers.",
    "answer": "50, 32",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Red blood cells are produced in adult mammals through a process called hematopoiesis , which occurs mainly in what specific part of the body?",
    "answer": "BONE MARROW",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Lightning Thief , The Sea of Monsters , The Titan's Curse , The Battle of the Labyrinth , and The Last Olympian are books in the young-adult series which features (and is named after) what main character, with the Olympians?",
    "answer": "PERCY JACKSON",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Wild , sweet , and pot are the three most familiar types of what herb (pictured)? The \"sweet\" type is most popular in Mediterranean cuisine, while the \"wild\" type is more commonly known as oregano . Click here",
    "answer": "MARJORAM",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "In this audio clip, Barbra Streisand sings a song that was originally written for the climax to what successful Broadway musical? Click here",
    "answer": "CATS",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "At the time of the Soviet Union's dissolution in December, 1991, which of the fifteen Soviet republics was the second -most populous?",
    "answer": "UKRAINE",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Name the business leader, baronet, philanthropist, and art collector who amassed his fortune as Britain's preeminent 19th Century sugar (and sugar cube) magnate.",
    "answer": "HENRY TATE",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "What took place on Saturday, March 24, 1984, at fictional Shermer High School in Shermer, Illinois?",
    "answer": "THE BREAKFAST CLUB",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "A thermistor (which converts heat into electrical voltage), an electric motor (electrical voltage into mechanical energy), and a microphone (sounds waves into electrical signals) are examples of what type of scientific device, whose name is derived from the Latin words for across and lead ?",
    "answer": "TRANSDUCER",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Dictionnaire raisonné des sciences, des arts et des métiers, par une société de gens de lettres, mis en ordre par M. Diderot de l'Académie des Sciences et Belles-Lettres de Prusse, et quant à la partie mathématique, par M. d'Alembert de l'Académie royale des Sciences de Paris, de celle de Prusse et de la Société royale de Londres is the cumbersome subtitle of an 18th Century work better known by its primary title, which is what?",
    "answer": "ENCYCLOPÉDIE",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The independent comedy film Tiny Furniture , in which liberal arts college graduate Aura returns home to New York to parent-funded malaise and directionlessness, provided the template for what television series?",
    "answer": "GIRLS",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The 1903 Hay–Herrán Treaty, which gave the USA the right to build a canal across the Isthmus of Panama, was an agreement between the United States and what other country (whose Senate rejected it, setting off events that resulted in the successful Panamanian revolt for independence, and ultimate completion of the Panama Canal in 1914)?",
    "answer": "COLOMBIA",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "In 1965, three students at London's Regent Street Polytechnic formed a band named Sigma 6, shortly thereafter renamed Architectural Abdabs, before inviting an erratic Camberwell Art School student to form a quartet which the newcomer named after two Carolina bluesmen. What, ultimately, became the name of this legendary rock group?",
    "answer": "PINK FLOYD",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Foehn , haboob , chinook , ostria , and williwaw are various names for different types of what?",
    "answer": "WIND",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Pictured here are works among those featured at the Salon d'Automne in Paris in 1905, which critic Louis Vauxcelles described as \"Donatello among the wild beasts.\" The quote (in its original French) inspired the name of the movement with which these works became associated. What is that name? Click here",
    "answer": "FAUVISM",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "At the turn of the 20th Century, the independent southern African republics the Orange Free State and the South African Republic (a.k.a. Transvaal) were known collectively as what \"Republics\", from the term for the settlers of the area?",
    "answer": "BOER REPUBLICS",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This photograph, taken in London's Tate Modern, displays paintings which are part of a series known as the Seagram Murals , by what artist? Click here",
    "answer": "MARK ROTHKO",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "For its final 117 years of existence, the Empire of Russia was ruled by five emperors who each had one of two different first names. Please provide both of these names.",
    "answer": "ALEXANDER, NICHOLAS",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "What do the letters P , Q , S , and D typically stand for in this image? Click here",
    "answer": "PRICE, QUANTITY, SUPPLY, DEMAND",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Anthony Lane, Andrew Sarris, Armond White, Wesley Morris, and Elvis Mitchell are all names most closely associated with what specific profession?",
    "answer": "FILM CRITICISM",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Diesel engines and gasoline engines are both piston-in-cylinder engines, but while a gasoline engine (a.k.a. Otto engine) takes an air-and-fuel mixture into the cylinder on the first piston stroke, a diesel engine instead takes in what, exactly?",
    "answer": "AIR (ONLY)",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The song excerpted here, P.M. Dawn's \"Looking Through Patient Eyes\", which reached #6 on the Billboard singles chart in 1993, samples a song that reached #1 on the same chart five years earlier by what artist? (45 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "GEORGE MICHAEL",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Known in its original Italian as a battachio , the English name for this prop used in Commedia dell'Arte has endured in modern times as a term for a popular style of physical comedy. What is that term?",
    "answer": "SLAPSTICK",
    "percent_correct": 89.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "With approximately 300 million native speakers, what language is the world's most widely spoken among those that are customarily written from right to left?",
    "answer": "ARABIC",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Name the politician who, since September 2010, has held the position of Leader of Her Majesty's Most Loyal Opposition in the United Kingdom.",
    "answer": "ED MILIBAND",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is a screenshot from what movie series? Click here",
    "answer": "SHARKNADO",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "\"Two fathoms\" is the literal meaning of what riverboat slang term and famous pseudonym?",
    "answer": "MARK TWAIN",
    "percent_correct": 84.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "A common symbol that is known in mathematics formally as a lemniscate and is associated with (among other things) the ancient symbol ouroboros and acid-free paper is most often used to represent what concept?",
    "answer": "INFINITY",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This photograph is featured on the cover of the June 1985 issue of what magazine? Click here",
    "answer": "NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "These shoes incorporate the signature feature of what French footwear designer? Click here",
    "answer": "CHRISTIAN LOUBOUTIN",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Although it's a term used today informally to refer to any poet, what title was awarded to a poet in medieval Ireland and Britain to signify membership in a privileged caste and responsibility for commemorating historic events and actions? It is similar but distinct from the Irish fili .",
    "answer": "BARD",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The most abundant isotope of hydrogen, known formally as hydrogen-1 or protium, contains no neutrons. What is the scientific name for the other stable hydrogen isotope that contains one neutron in its nucleus and is also known as hydrogen-d or \"heavy hydrogen\"?",
    "answer": "DEUTERIUM",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Augusto César Sandino was, until his assassination in 1934, a revolutionary who led guerrilla resistance to U.S. occupation forces in what country, where he remains a national hero?",
    "answer": "NICARAGUA",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name any one of the four films that features the on-screen comic partnership of Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor.",
    "answer": "SILVER STREAK; STIR CRAZY; SEE NO EVIL, HEAR NO EVIL; ANOTHER YOU",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Provide the single word that fills in the blanks in all the following instances: Ludwig van Beethoven's Grosse ______, Op. 133 ; Dmitri Shostakovich's Prelude and ______  #4 in E minor ; and J.S. Bach's The Art of ______ .",
    "answer": "FUGE/FUGUE",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Among the original \"Seven Commandments of Animalism\" from George Orwell's Animal Farm , the first states \"Whatever goes upon two legs is an enemy.\" What word is missing from the second commandment, as follows? \"Whatever goes upon four legs, or has _______, is a friend.\"",
    "answer": "WINGS",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the man, U.S. Secretary of State from 1947 to 1949 and Secretary of Defense from 1950 to 1951, who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1953.",
    "answer": "GEORGE MARSHALL",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Through virtually the entire run of the animated sitcom King of the Hill , main protagonist Hank Hill works as a salesman of what product?",
    "answer": "PROPANE (AND PROPANE ACCESSORIES)",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The Danish physicist Hans Christian Ørsted gave his name to the unit oersted , now replaced by the SI unit ampere per meter , which both measure what? The Earth's is about 0.5 oersted.",
    "answer": "MAGNETIC FIELD",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Of all islands with a population greater than 1 million, the world's most densely populated is New York's Manhattan Island, which covers 23 square miles. Close behind, with over 15 million inhabitants on its 240 square miles, is Salsette Island, which sits just off the western coast of what nation?",
    "answer": "INDIA",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The calamities in a 2014 comedy film include gum in the title character's hair, a dead car battery, a baby at a job interview, a failed driving test, an overdose on cough medicine, and numerous others. What is the name of this film's title character?",
    "answer": "ALEXANDER (AND THE TERRIBLE, HORRIBLE, NO GOOD, VERY BAD DAY)",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What primary ingredient is shared by the dishes aligot , criques , rösti , hachis Parmentier , and gratin dauphinois ?",
    "answer": "POTATOES",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Two rounds of bilateral negotiations between the Soviet Union and the United States regarding armament control, the first of which commenced in Helsinki in 1969 and the latter of which concluded in Vienna in 1979, are each best known today by what abbreviation (with a numerical suffix)?",
    "answer": "SALT",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In 2014, the adidas Golden Boot, which is given to the top goal scorer in the FIFA World Cup, was awarded to attacking midfielder James Rodríguez. For what national team does James play?",
    "answer": "COLOMBIA",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "In American television history, three series have ended their runs with their final seasons ranked at the top of the Nielsen ratings. This occurred in 1956–57, 1967–68, and 1997–98. Name any one of these three series.",
    "answer": "I LOVE LUCY, THE ANDY GRIFFITH SHOW, SEINFELD",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Tappi Tíkarrass; Kukl; and, most successfully, Sykurmolarnir were bands that featured singer-songwriter Björk Guðmundsdóttir as vocalist. What is the English translation of the word Sykurmolarnir ?",
    "answer": "SUGARCUBES",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "For some insects, specific terms are used for the pupa stage of holometabolous development (coming between the juvenile larva and fully mature imago ). For mosquitoes, the term is tumbler . What is the equivalent term for butterflies?",
    "answer": "CHRYSALIS/NYMPHA",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "With his Best Supporting Actor nomination at the 2011 Academy Awards (portraying Sir Laurence Olivier, to whom he has been compared), this British filmmaker became the first to be nominated in five different categories: Best Supporting Actor, Best Actor and Best Director (1989), Best Live Action Short Film (1992), and Best Adapted Screenplay (1996). Notably, he has yet to win.",
    "answer": "KENNETH BRANAGH",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "A series of three orchestral suites written by George Frideric Handel that premiered in concert in July 1717, and was (possibly) written to gain the favor of King George I of Great Britain, is best known today by what name?",
    "answer": "WATER MUSIC",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is a former logo, from 1956, for what NFL team? Click here",
    "answer": "NEW YORK GIANTS",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The current President of Kenya, who was elected to the position in March, 2013, is the son of the first President of Kenya, who served from 1964 to 1978. What last name do these men share?",
    "answer": "KENYATTA",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "A complicated set of diplomatic conflicts and border disputes that is known collectively as the \"Schleswig-Holstein Question\" existed for the better part of 100 years (or more) between, originally, the German Confederation and what other nation?",
    "answer": "DENMARK",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "A traditional (and chaotic) 1980s Italian-American wedding and reception provide the setting for a popular immersive and largely improvisational theatre event that has run in over 200 cities across North America, including for over 20 years in New York beginning in 1985. The piece is named after the bride and groom. What are their names?",
    "answer": "TONY, TINA",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Although successful versions of the song \"Dancing in the Street\" were released by the Grateful Dead, Van Halen, and Mick Jagger and David Bowie (as a duo),  it was first recorded in 1964 by what Motown group?",
    "answer": "MARTHA AND THE VANDELLAS",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "As two of the three men (with Émile Durkheim) widely credited with founding sociology as a field of study, Karl Marx and this fellow German held some views that could hardly differ more. For example, whereas Marx saw economics as the major force in social change, this man attributed it to religion. Who was this Prussian-born philosopher, social theorist, and liberal German Democrat?",
    "answer": "MAX WEBER",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What Middle Eastern country's unique multi-confessional constitution (specifically via the unwritten National Pact of 1943) stipulates that the republic's President should always be a Maronite Christian, whereas its Prime Minister should always be a Sunni Muslim?",
    "answer": "LEBANON",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The critically panned 2014 film The Best of Me is the ninth film to be adapted from the works of what American novelist of romantic fiction?",
    "answer": "NICHOLAS SPARKS",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "A surveyor's notation is the best known name for what is also known variously (and unofficially) as Chhogori, Dapsang, Kechu, Lamba Pahar, and Godwin-Austen. What is that notation?",
    "answer": "K2",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Who is, by far , Major League Baseball's career leader in stolen bases, with 1,406? (Lou Brock is #2 with 938.)",
    "answer": "RICKEY HENDERSON",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "In addition to being its continent's southernmost point, the rocky promontory known as Cape Agulhas is the official dividing point between what two oceans?",
    "answer": "ATLANTIC, INDIAN",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The gesture from American Sign Language demonstrated here is most commonly used to express what statement? Click here",
    "answer": "I LOVE YOU",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Widely regarded as one of the finest achievements in Japanese literature—and, perhaps, the world's first novel—is a work, written by Lady Murasaki, which chronicles court society and romantic love during the Heian period. It is best known in English as what?",
    "answer": "THE TALE OF GENJI",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Songs recorded at the Winterland Ballroom in San Francisco and the Long Island Arena in Commack, New York, in the summer of 1975, are among the tracks on what would become the most successful live album in rock history, eventually selling over 11 million copies worldwide. What is the name of this double album?",
    "answer": "FRAMPTON COMES ALIVE!",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Book of the Marvels of the World ( Livre des Merveilles du Monde in its native French, and known in Italian as Il Milione ) was written around the year 1300 by Rustichello da Pisa, based on accounts he heard while incarcerated with what Genoan prison mate?",
    "answer": "MARCO POLO",
    "percent_correct": 65.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The first-ever controlled landing of a spacecraft on a comet occurred when a robotic lander built by the European Space Agency (ESA) touched down on comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko on November 12, 2014. The space probe launched by the ESA is named Rosetta . What is the name of Rosetta's lander module that made physical contact with the comet itself?",
    "answer": "PHILAE",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the actor, born near Alsace in 1918 and father of 48 before his death at age 13, who was credited in the mid-1920s as saving Warner Bros. studio (where he was known as \"the mortgage lifter\") from bankruptcy. He is said to have earned $6,000 per month; have received 12,000 fan letters per week; have been insured for $100,000; and have had his own valet, chef, limo, and driver.",
    "answer": "RIN TIN TIN",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "For culinary purposes, edible fish are often divided into two groups. The demersal group, also known as white fish , includes the cod and perch families, which typically live on or near the seafloor, whereas the pelagic group includes sardines, herring, salmon, and tuna, which live away from the bottom. What is the most common term for this latter group, used often in contrast to white fish ?",
    "answer": "OILY FISH",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The Ecumenical Patriarch , who serves as the spiritual leader of Orthodox Christianity and is currently Bartholomew I, is formally the Archbishop of what city?",
    "answer": "CONSTANTINOPLE (ISTANBUL)",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Among the 26 individuals inducted into the inaugural class of the U.S. National Track and Field Hall of Fame in 1974 were two women. Identify either of these superstar athletes.",
    "answer": "BABE DIDRIKSON ZAHARIAS, WILMA RUDOLPH",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The most popular English foundling in the literature of the late 1740s shares his name with the most popular Welsh singer in the music of the late 1960s. What is that name?",
    "answer": "TOM JONES",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "A historical series that began in Ottawa, Illinois, on August 21, 1858, and ended in Alton, Illinois, on October 15 of that same year ultimately resulted, the following January, in the re-election of what incumbent?",
    "answer": "STEPHEN A. DOUGLAS",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "From 1958 until 1984, the republic highlighted in green in this map was known by what name? Click here",
    "answer": "UPPER VOLTA",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The title of what Neil Diamond hit single refers not, as it might seem, to a prostitute (or \"store-bought woman\"), but rather to a type of wine?",
    "answer": "CRACKLIN' ROSIE",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What Swiss dish, typically served for breakfast, originally consisted of apples, oats, milk, and nuts when invented by physician Maximilian Bircher-Benner around the turn of the 20th century? Today, it often also includes other grains, fruits, and seeds.",
    "answer": "MUESLI",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "GAAP stands for \"generally accepted accounting principles.\" An alternative and largely theoretical set of accounting principles, abbreviated LGAP , dictates full and transparent disclosure of all information, including information not normally reported under GAAP, such as all off-balance sheet items. After whom are the LGAP named?",
    "answer": "LADY GODIVA",
    "percent_correct": 11.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "In the United States gubernatorial elections of 2014, a Republican incumbent lost to a Democratic challenger in only one of the 36 governorships that were up for grabs. The incumbent's deep unpopularity has been attributed to his views regarding gun control, Medicaid expansion, and same-sex marriage, as well as residual fallout from a child sex abuse scandal. Identify the state .",
    "answer": "PENNSYLVANIA",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The marriage of Edgar Linton and Catherine Earnshaw triggers rage and misery that lie at the center of what classic novel?",
    "answer": "WUTHERING HEIGHTS",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What is the name of the American television channel, co-produced by the entertainment company Discovery Communications, that debuted on New Year's Day 2011, replacing the Discovery Health Channel? Among its original programming are the three Tyler Perry–produced series The Haves and the Have Nots , Love Thy Neighbor , and Tyler Perry's For Better or Worse .",
    "answer": "OWN (OPRAH WINFREY NETWORK)",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Identify the tennis champion pictured here. Click here",
    "answer": "CAROLINE WOZNIACKI",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Based on clubs formed by a country school principal in Ohio in 1902, a \"Rural Youth Division\" was established by the Cooperative Extension Service of the U.S. Department of Agriculture in 1914, and took what official name five years later, which it retains today?",
    "answer": "4-H",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The geographic area precisely coterminous with Richmond County in New York State is most commonly referred to as what?",
    "answer": "STATEN ISLAND",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "The Daniel Burnham–designed building in this photograph, taken from above the intersection of Oxford and Orchard Streets in London, is the second-largest department store in the United Kingdom. It is the flagship for what department store chain? Click here",
    "answer": "SELFRIDGES",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Although this late 19th/early 20th century painter's ambition led him toward genre paintings and murals, he's probably best known for his vast and popular output of portraiture, including the controversial Portrait of Madame X (pictured). Click here",
    "answer": "JOHN SINGER SARGENT",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The festival in the Western Christian Church known as Quadragesima (Latin for \"fortieth\") is better known by what other name?",
    "answer": "LENT",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The Broadway musical Kismet is adapted from the work of Russian Romantic composer Alexander Borodin—specifically, his string quartets, symphonic poem In the Steppes of Central Asia , and his unfinished opera that features what titular prince?",
    "answer": "PRINCE IGOR",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The most populous urban area in Germany, which is located within the state of North Rhine-Westphalia and includes the cities of Essen, Dortmund, Bochum, and others, is most commonly referred to by what name, after the river that forms (or runs near) its southern border?",
    "answer": "RUHR",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The French king who embarked on the Third Crusade in 1190, the Spanish king whose Armada was defeated in 1588, the \"Good\" Burgundian Duke whose troops captured Joan of Arc in 1430, and the Macedonian king who mastered all of independent Greece in 338 BC all shared what first name?",
    "answer": "PHILIP",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Zymurgy is a bimonthly magazine published in the United States by a not-for-profit association of members who share what hobby?",
    "answer": "HOMEBREWING",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is the board for what popular game? Click here",
    "answer": "TICKET TO RIDE",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "The dish tamagoyaki , which often appears on Japanese (and especially sushi) restaurant menus as simply tamago , literally translates to English as \"grilled\" what?",
    "answer": "EGG",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "During the 1990s, four Saturday Night Live castmembers served as regular anchors of the fake-news sketch \"Weekend Update\". Name any two of these four men.",
    "answer": "DENNIS MILLER, KEVIN NEALON, NORM MACDONALD, COLIN QUINN",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Four national capital cities sit on the banks of the Danube River, more than any other river in the world. Name any two of these four cities.",
    "answer": "BELGRADE, BRATISLAVA, BUDAPEST, VIENNA",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "\"Upon the whole, therefore, it is the judgment of this court, that it appears by the record before us that the plaintiff in error is not a citizen of Missouri, in the sense in which that word is used in the Constitution; and that the Circuit Court of the United States, for that reason, had no jurisdiction in the case, and could give no judgment in it. Its judgment for the defendant must, consequently, be reversed, and a mandate issued, directing the suit to be dismissed for want of jurisdiction.\" Who was the plaintiff in the U.S. Supreme Court case whose majority opinion ended thus?",
    "answer": "DRED SCOTT",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The Donbass, the Rapid Trident military exercise, Malaysia Airlines Flight 17, and \"little green men\" are all relevant to a current conflict between whom?",
    "answer": "UKRAINE, RUSSIA",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "The shipyards that constructed 747 U.S. vessels during WWII, a pioneering health maintenance organization that is today the largest of its kind, major aluminum and steel concerns, and a leading non-profit organization focusing on national and global health issues and policy were all started by (and named after) what American industrialist?",
    "answer": "HENRY J. KAISER",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Various peace treaties between Great Britain and \"Pirate Coast\" rulers beginning in 1820 created what came to be known as Trucial States , which were collectively a British protectorate until six of them federated to form a new independent country in 1971. Name any one of these six former Trucial States.",
    "answer": "ABU DHABI, AJMAN, DUBAI, FUJAIRAH, SHARJAH, UMM AL QAIWAIN",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "In the early 19th century, a Massachusetts estate containing recently planted Williams' bon chrétien pear trees was purchased, and became the genesis for the introduction of the variety into the United States. The man who purchased the estate named the variety after himself, unaware of its heritage, and that name endures today in North America for this most popular variety. What was the man's last name?",
    "answer": "BARTLETT",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name this rock band, who were possibly named after 17 elements of the periodic table (specifically, scandium, yttrium, and the fifteen lanthanides). (28 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "RARE EARTH",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Identify either of the fellow actors who are the famous parents of this woman. Click here",
    "answer": "MELANIE GRIFFITH, DON JOHNSON",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What is the literary term—from Middle English for \"poor\" or \"worthless\" and likely the diminutive for a certain animal, and comparable to the German knittelvers (\"badly knit verse\")—that describes verse with an irregular meter and loose construction? The term is often used for any clumsily executed and rhythmically plodding poetry.",
    "answer": "DOGGEREL",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What is the name of this character? Click here",
    "answer": "STEVE",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "The mural in this photograph was commissioned in the late 15th century by Ludovico Sforza, who at the time was the Duke of what Lombard duchy? The painting remains today in the duchy's namesake city. Click here",
    "answer": "MILAN",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "James P. Gray, Matt Gonzalez, Peter Camejo, Winona LaDuke, Pat Choate, and James Stockdale are the last six individuals to finish in third place in the election for what?",
    "answer": "VICE-PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Symphony No. 6 in B Minor, Op. 74, whose title is most often referred to by its French translation, Pathétique , was the last completed symphony of what legendary composer, who died nine days after leading its first performance in October of 1893?",
    "answer": "PYOTR TCHAIKOVSKY",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "There are 193 current United Nations member states. Based on their official names/designations used for seating in General Assembly sessions, every letter of the alphabet is the first letter of at least one member state (e.g. Afghanistan, Bahamas, Cambodia, Denmark, etc.) except for two . One is \"X\" (that is, there is no U.N. member state whose name begins with the letter \"X\"). What is the other letter?",
    "answer": "W",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "The IPO of this company, which occurred in August 1995, is often credited as kickstarting the dot-com bubble of the late 1990s. Although it rose from an offering price of $28 to close its first day at $58.25 (with an intraday high of $75 and ultimate peak of $174), the company was acquired three years later, accelerating its downfall, and its signature product was defunct by 2008. Name the company.",
    "answer": "NETSCAPE",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Folger Shakespeare Library, home to the world's largest collection of William Shakespeare's printed works, as well as other important cross-disciplinary collections of rare books and manuscripts from the early modern period, is located in what city?",
    "answer": "WASHINGTON, DC",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What word, which is also a man's name, best fits within the red box in this diagram? Click here",
    "answer": "CHUCK",
    "percent_correct": 83.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "A polyhedron is a solid figure with four or more plane faces. The five \"Platonic solids\" are regular polyhedra, with all faces the same size and shape. Which Platonic solid is missing from this list? Tetrahedron , cube , octahedron , icosahedron .",
    "answer": "DODECAHEDRON",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The German visionary war theorist who served for 30 years as chief of staff of the Prussian Army was the uncle of the man who led the German Army at the onset of WWI. What name did these men share?",
    "answer": "HELMUTH VON MOLTKE",
    "percent_correct": 8.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The Ancient Greek word χείρ , the source of \"chir-\" in the words chiropractic , chiropody , and chirality , translates to English as what?",
    "answer": "HAND",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The English village of Silverstone, in the East Midlands county of Northamptonshire, is the location of Great Britain's premier event in what sport?",
    "answer": "AUTO RACING/FORMULA ONE",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "These dogs are all members of what breed, thought to be one of the oldest still in existence? Click here",
    "answer": "CHOW CHOW (CHOW)",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "According to its first post-statehood census in 2011, 45% of the population of this Balkan country's 700,000 citizens identify ethnically as Crnogorci , with another 29% Srbi , 9% Bošnjaci , 5% Shqiptarët ( Albanci ), and 1% Hrvati . What is the country?",
    "answer": "MONTENEGRO",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What is the expression that is typically (and famously) represented in scripts and episode titles for the television show The Simpsons as \"(annoyed grunt)\"?",
    "answer": "D'OH",
    "percent_correct": 95.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This term, derived from Latin via Italian for cave or crypt and used originally for an Ancient Roman style of decorative art, is today used in an art context for a highly fanciful, fantastic, and incongruous form that subverts the natural order by depicting figures metamorphosing into one another. What is the term?",
    "answer": "GROTESQUE",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What (in English) is the central ingredient of the classic Spanish specialty known natively as chipirones en su tinta ?",
    "answer": "SQUID",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What word is the English translation of the Russian Солнце , Hindi सूर्य ( Sūrya ), Tagalog Araw , Turkish Güneş , Swahili jua , Polish Słońce , Japanese 太陽 ( Taiyō ), and Greek Ήλιος ( Í̱lios )? Note—if some characters do not render properly in your browser, follow this link to view an image: Click here",
    "answer": "SUN",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "As measured by market capitalization, Apple Inc. is the most valuable company on the NASDAQ Stock Market (or any public stock exchange). What is Apple's four-letter ticker symbol on the NASDAQ?",
    "answer": "AAPL",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "British General John Burgoyne's failed attempt to isolate New England from the middle and southern colonies during the American Revolutionary War culminated in the late summer/early fall of 1777 at the Battles of Freeman's Farm and Bemis Heights. Collectively, these battles became associated  in the historical record with what town?",
    "answer": "SARATOGA",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The capital city of Chile, the home stadium of Newcastle United F.C., the brewery that produces Guinness beer, and the current home of Side Show on Broadway are all named after an individual best known as what in English?",
    "answer": "ST. JAMES",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Among the four major North American professional sports leagues, baseball slugger Barry Bonds has won the second-most Most Valuable Player awards, with seven. Who has the most, with nine?",
    "answer": "WAYNE GRETZKY",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the most common name for the notably soft mineral hydrous magnesium silicate , Mg 3 Si 4 O 10 (OH) 2 ?",
    "answer": "TALC",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the actress in this photograph. Click here",
    "answer": "ROSALIND RUSSELL",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Typically, acne is caused by blockage and inflammation of what skin glands, due to the overproduction of the glands' oily secretion (from which the gland takes its name)?",
    "answer": "SEBACEOUS GLANDS",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "With the help of his sister Estelle Axton, Tennessee businessman Jim Stewart founded the seminal record label Satellite Records in 1957 and—after the discovery of another California-based Satellite Records—changed its name in 1961 to what new name, which it retained through its 1977 bankruptcy?",
    "answer": "STAX RECORDS",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "This English navigator sailed with Captain James Cook on explorations of Australia, New Zealand, and the Hawaiian Islands, but he is best remembered today for his extensive and precise survey work on the Pacific coast of northern North America, where numerous locations have been named in his honor (including a major city in the region). Name the man.",
    "answer": "GEORGE VANCOUVER",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Whereas most leavened bread is yeast risen, the type of bread that instead uses NaHCO 3 as a leavening agent is best known generally as what? Specific examples include Scottish bannocks, Australian damper, and a popular Irish namesake variety.",
    "answer": "SODA BREAD",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Name the successful and enduring 1959 play, the first written by an African American woman to be produced on Broadway, whose title comes from the 1951 Langston Hughes poem \"Harlem\".",
    "answer": "A RAISIN IN THE SUN",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "What American organization holds membership in the international federation that also includes Israel's Magen David Adom , Turkey's Türk Kızılayı , and Saudi Arabia's SRCA ?",
    "answer": "AMERICAN RED CROSS",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The Hindu concept of Trimurti manifests the cosmic functions of the Supreme Being as represented by three forms. Identify any two of the three most common personifications of these functions.",
    "answer": "BRAHMA, VISHNU, SHIVA",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In the law of physics most commonly expressed as PV = nRT , the constant \"R\" is most often referred to as the \"______ constant.\" (Fill in the blank.)",
    "answer": "GAS",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In his 21-year baseball career, which ended in 2001, this Hall of Fame shortstop won the American League's Most Valuable Player Award twice, in 1983 and 1991. Name the player.",
    "answer": "CAL RIPKEN, JR.",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "In modern digital photo cameras, the index rating for sensitivity to light (exposure index) is normally designated by a three-letter acronym. What is that acronym?",
    "answer": "ISO",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Parkside, Platteville, River Falls, Stevens Point, Stout, and Whitewater are all campuses of four-year schools in what state's public university system?",
    "answer": "WISCONSIN",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL63",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This excerpt is from the fourth and final symphony of what composer? (49 seconds) Click here",
    "answer": "JOHANNES BRAHMS",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Marion Ravenwood, a one-time barkeep in remote Nepal with a sarcastic wit and a very high tolerance for alcohol, is the sometimes girlfriend of what famous film character?",
    "answer": "INDIANA JONES",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The 24th and final Book of Homer's Iliad ends with the funeral of what Trojan hero?",
    "answer": "HECTOR",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "This cropped photograph, along with the redacted inset photo, appeared on a hit record album released in January of 1971. Name the two-year-old child in these photos, who is the thirty-five-year-old artist on the record. Click here",
    "answer": "ELVIS PRESLEY",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What unit of measurement is defined as the force needed to move a 1 kg object so that it accelerates at 1 m/s 2 ? It is also used as a measure of weight, where one unit is the weight of a medium-sized apple, roughly.",
    "answer": "NEWTON",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Of the items that shaped the legacy of British conservative politician Benjamin Disraeli, among the most prominent was his bitter, decades-long rivalry with what Liberal leader, who himself served four times as Prime Minister?",
    "answer": "WILLIAM GLADSTONE",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "The culinary preparation known as duxelles (used in various dishes served à la duxelles ) typically consists of chopped shallots, onions, and herbs, with what other main ingredient, all sautéed in butter?",
    "answer": "MUSHROOMS",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is an assortment of real-life items which relate to the standard version of a particular board game, with one item missing. What is the missing item? Click here",
    "answer": "ROPE",
    "percent_correct": 89.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Episode plots in what acclaimed, technology-savvy CBS drama series have involved the internet search company \"Chumhum\", the social and news website \"Scabbit\", legal issues surrounding the invention of Bitcoin, and a ransomware attack?",
    "answer": "THE GOOD WIFE",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the man who seized control of the Pakistan government via a military coup d'état in October of 1999, and served as the country's President from 2001 until his resignation under threat of impeachment in August, 2008.",
    "answer": "PERVEZ MUSHARRAF",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "A controversial and massive work of post-minimalist public art titled Tilted Arc , which was erected in Manhattan's Federal Plaza in 1981 and removed in 1989 after years of debate and legal action, was conceived by what American sculptor?",
    "answer": "RICHARD SERRA",
    "percent_correct": 13.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "There are exactly two elements represented in the periodic table by single letters whose standard names (in English) do not begin with those letters. What are those elements' names? (As a counterexample, Oxygen begins with its symbol, O .)",
    "answer": "POTASSIUM, TUNGSTEN",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The principality of Monaco is traditionally divided into four Quartiers : Monaco-Ville, La Condamine, Fontvielle, and what fourth?",
    "answer": "MONTE CARLO",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "In 2011, a low-calorie (specifically, a TEN-calorie) variety of what popular soft drink was released in the United States, with a marketing message aimed at men—most directly in its tagline, \"It's Not for Women.\"?",
    "answer": "DR PEPPER",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the only man who was elected governor of two different U.S. states, as well as the only man to be twice-elected President of the Republic of Texas.",
    "answer": "SAM HOUSTON",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Who played the title character in the critically acclaimed 1971 film thriller Klute ?",
    "answer": "DONALD SUTHERLAND",
    "percent_correct": 18.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Eldest , Brisingr , and Inheritance are the second-through-fourth books in author Christopher Paolini's Inheritance Cycle tetralogy. What is the name of the first novel in the series?",
    "answer": "ERAGON",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In May of 1796, pioneering English physician Edward Jenner inoculated his gardener's young son with pus from a milkmaid's blister, thereby rendering him immune to what infectious disease?",
    "answer": "SMALLPOX",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The Manzanares River, pictured here, passes through what national capital city? Click here",
    "answer": "MADRID",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The name of the Rastafari movement is taken from Ras Tafari Makonnen, the personal pre-coronation name of the African emperor who was later (and better) known as what?",
    "answer": "HAILE SELASSIE",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "A Yiddish word for \"stuffed\" is applied commonly (and nearly exclusively) to a particular classic Jewish dish, suitable for serving during the Sabbath (when cooking is not permitted). What is that word?",
    "answer": "GEFILTE",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "A special type of quadrilateral defined as having two pairs of sides, with each pair made up of adjacent sides that equal in length, is sometimes referred to as a deltoid , but is better known in geometry as, appropriately, a what?",
    "answer": "KITE",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "What last name do these brothers share? Click here",
    "answer": "KOCH",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Manitoulin Island, the world's largest \"freshwater island\", sits within Georgian Bay, an inlet which protrudes from what lake?",
    "answer": "LAKE HURON",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Following the 1978 implosion of the Sex Pistols, master media manipulator Malcolm McLaren collected three members of Adam and the Ants (basically, the Ants) and a fourteen-year-old part-time laundress and Burmese immigrant to form what new band, which was perhaps only slightly less controversial than the Pistols?",
    "answer": "BOW WOW WOW",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "OPI, Seche, Sally Hansen, Deborah Lippman, and CND are all fashion brands most associated with what product?",
    "answer": "NAIL POLISH",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The war which resulted in the U.S. acquiring some 500,000 square miles of new territory is widely regarded as the first U.S. war to be photographed, the first covered by newspaper correspondents, and the first fought primarily on foreign soil. In what country was this war fought?",
    "answer": "MEXICO",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "In June 2013, National Security Agency subcontractor Edward Snowden met with journalists Glenn Greenwald and Laura Poitras and revealed details of classified United States government surveillance programs. This meeting took place at the Mira Hotel in what city?",
    "answer": "HONG KONG",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "A Los Angeles physician awakens, and turns to see a yellow Labrador retriever walking through a thicket of bamboo. So begins what television series?",
    "answer": "LOST",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Give the full name of the controversial soprano, often falsely reported at the time of her death in 2006 as the aunt of an American military general, who was renowned particularly for her lieder interpretations and signature portrayals of Richard Strauss and Mozart heroines.",
    "answer": "ELISABETH SCHWARZKOPF",
    "percent_correct": 7.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "In many computer operating systems, notably DOS and Unix, what is the four-letter command used to display a message (a string of text) on the terminal or output to a file? In many computer operating systems, notably DOS and Unix, what is the four-letter command used to display a message (a string of text) on the terminal or output to a file?",
    "answer": "ECHO",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The River Alma, Balaclava, and Inkerman were major battle sites of what 1850s war, which is also notable for the nursing of Florence Nightingale and the reporting of The Times correspondent William Howard Russell?",
    "answer": "CRIMEAN WAR",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "An independent travel booktore owner in central London, a child psychologist father-to-be, an ungentlemanly publishing company boss, and Prime Minister of the United Kingdom are among the prominent film roles portrayed by what actor?",
    "answer": "HUGH GRANT",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Certain insects and other arthropods possess what are known as stridulatory organs , which are used specifically to produce what?",
    "answer": "SOUND",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In finance and financial analysis, what feline term is used colloquially to describe a small and temporary phase of recovery that occurs during a prolonged period of decline, after which is a quick and sustained continuation of the downward trend?",
    "answer": "DEAD CAT BOUNCE",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Fulton J. Sheen, who was the only Emmy winner in the DuMont television network's ten years of existence, hosted for many years (on DuMont and elsewhere) the program Life is Worth Living . What was Sheen's primary occupation?",
    "answer": "CATHOLIC PRIEST (BISHOP/ARCHBISHOP)",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Name the basketball Hall of Famer who won the Michigan High School Class A Boys Basketball Championship in 1977, the NCAA Men's Division I Basketball Championship in 1979, and his first NBA Finals in 1980.",
    "answer": "MAGIC JOHNSON",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Of the two title characters in the sixth (and penultimate) book of the Harry Potter series, Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince , the second (after Harry himself) is better known throughout the series by what name?",
    "answer": "SEVERUS SNAPE",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Name the famous 1927 musical by Jerome Kern and Oscar Hammerstein II, regarded by some as the first successful, totally American operetta, which includes the classics \"Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man\", \"Make Believe\", \"Why Do I Love You\", and \"Ol' Man River\".",
    "answer": "SHOW BOAT",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What is the German translation of the French word montagne ?",
    "answer": "BERG",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the anatomical term for a muscle that bends a limb, working as an antagonist in opposition to extensors ? Examples in the human body include the biceps , deltoid , and the sartorius ?",
    "answer": "FLEXOR",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Of the twelve studio albums released by the rock band Van Halen, two of them, released consecutively in the mid-1980s, have titles which are four-digit numbers. Please give either of those two numbers.",
    "answer": "1984, 5150",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "___forum , ___Review , and ___news : these are all names of magazines which are missing the same first three letters—letters which spell the genre these magazines cover. What are the three missing letters?",
    "answer": "ART",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "\"Dear King Philip Came Over For Good Soup.\" In this mnemonic, the word \"soup\" stands in for what other word?",
    "answer": "SPECIES",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "The Radiant Child , a crawling baby in a halo of light, was the personal logo of what American artist?",
    "answer": "KEITH HARING",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the Academy Award-winning director who was screenwriter (but not director) of the films Midnight Express , Conan the Barbarian , Scarface , and Evita .",
    "answer": "OLIVER STONE",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What expression, popular from the early days of WWII, is used to describe enemy sympathizers who may provide active assistance to invading forces? The term originates from the Spanish Civil War, when sympathizers supported a quartet of rebel battalions advancing on Madrid.",
    "answer": "FIFTH COLUMN",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Massachusetts-born 19th c. publisher Samuel French first achieved success publishing works of what literary form? The namesake company he founded in the 1850s continues to dominate the particular market to this day.",
    "answer": "PLAYS",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "There are two rivers in Africa which each has two different countries named after it. Please name both rivers.",
    "answer": "CONGO, NIGER",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The 1,099-mile-long Baku-Tbilisi-Ceyhan pipeline transports crude oil originating from fields in what body of water?",
    "answer": "CASPIAN SEA",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What was private investigator and guesthouse-resident Thomas S. Magnum's favorite baseball team?",
    "answer": "DETROIT TIGERS",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Shortly after the conclusion of WWII hostilities in Europe in May of 1945, the #1 single on the Billboard \"Best Sellers in Stores\" chart was, fittingly, \"Sentimental Journey\", which became an unofficial homecoming theme for returning veterans. This original recording, backed by Les Brown and His Band of Renown, was the first #1 hit for what artist, who would soon become a major star of music and film in her own right?",
    "answer": "DORIS DAY",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The paradoxically cordial-sounding Treaty of Friendship, Co-operation, and Mutual Assistance was formed in May of 1955 as the military complement to an economic organization formally named the Council for Mutual Economic Assistance . By what name is this treaty best known?",
    "answer": "WARSAW PACT",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The ultramafic igneous rock known as kimberlite is today the world's primary source of what mineral with important scientific and industrial applications?",
    "answer": "DIAMOND",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Henry Wadsworth Longfellow poem which appeared in his 1863 Tales of a Wayside Inn collection as \"The Landlord's Tale\" describes legendary (and largely fictional) exploits of what American hero?",
    "answer": "PAUL REVERE",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Provide the name that completes this list: Elmer Layden, Bert Bell, Austin Gunsel, Pete Rozelle, Paul Tagliabue.",
    "answer": "ROGER GOODELL",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What Asian municipality of roughly 250,000 people, planned by Edwin Lutyens and Herbert Baker and built from 1912 to 1929, was inaugurated in 1931 as capital, and remains its country's seat of government today?",
    "answer": "NEW DELHI",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "A one-act play by David Belasco and John Luther Long, which ran on Broadway for 24 performances in 1900, would likely be totally forgotten today had Giacomo Puccini not created an opera from it four years later—and had a smash Broadway musical adapted in part from the opera not been produced 85 years afterwards. What name do the original play and Puccini's opera share?",
    "answer": "MADAME BUTTERFLY",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Rounded to the nearest thousand , what is the current level of the NASDAQ Composite index?",
    "answer": "5000",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The plot of the original Star Wars film (Episode IV) involves plans to the Galactic Empire's Death Star being stolen by spies for the Rebel Alliance. Near the beginning of the film, these plans are hidden, by Alderaan Princess Leia Organa, where?",
    "answer": "R2-D2",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Of the official cookie varieties offered for sale during fundraisers for the Girl Scouts of the USA, which is the only one to have the Girl Scouts logo embossed on the cookie's face?",
    "answer": "TREFOILS/SHORTBREAD",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The popular card game Klondike , which uses a standard 52-card deck with no Jokers, is also known (and perhaps better known) by an alternate name that is actually the category of card game under which Klondike falls. What is that other name?",
    "answer": "SOLITAIRE (PATIENCE)",
    "percent_correct": 67.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Mick Jones, guitarist and founding member of the rock band Foreigner, is the (former) stepfather of what current chart-topping English musician and producer (as well as his twin sisters)?",
    "answer": "MARK RONSON",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Following France's humiliating defeat at the hands of the North German Confederation (the soon-to-be German Empire) in 1871, a socialist revolutionary uprising gained rule in the nation's capital city via the election of a municipal council, which was hastily and very violently suppressed by the monarchist French government by May of that year. What is the common name given both to this council and the uprising itself?",
    "answer": "PARIS COMMUNE",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Treatment of animal fats or vegetable oils with sodium hydroxide or potassium hydroxide is the fundamental process used most often to create what?",
    "answer": "SOAP",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The verb in the following sentence is in the present tense; please rewrite the sentence with the verb in the present perfect tense. I enjoy eating cheese.",
    "answer": "I HAVE ENJOYED EATING CHEESE",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "What is the term from mathematics for the fractional part of a common logarithm (i.e. the part after the decimal point)? It's also used more generally for the fractional part of any real number—for example, the .259 in 8.259.",
    "answer": "MANTISSA",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Tomorrow, I'll think of some way to get him back. After all, tomorrow is another day. Thus ends what novel, in lines spoken by the story's vain, spoiled, shrewd, strong-willed, thrice-married heroine?",
    "answer": "GONE WITH THE WIND",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "What term from music, derived from a Greek word for \"song\" or \"tune\", refers to a group of notes sung to a single syllable of text, normally including a primary note and ornamentation? Gregorian chants are an old example; more recent examples are basically anything by Whitney Houston or Mariah Carey.",
    "answer": "MELISMA",
    "percent_correct": 19.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Name the hurler, the winner of the National League Cy Young Award after the 1969, 1973, and 1975 seasons, who is the only member of the Baseball Hall of Fame in Cooperstown, New York, whose plaque sports a New York Mets cap.",
    "answer": "TOM SEAVER",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Name the actor who plays Senator Gil John Biggs in the TV series Alpha House , Congressman Scott Talley in the film The Campaign , Congressman Chuck Long in the film Evan Almighty , and Speaker of the House Glenallen Walken in the TV series The West Wing .",
    "answer": "JOHN GOODMAN",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "\"I do not believe that the president loves America. He doesn't love you. And he doesn't love me. He wasn't brought up the way you were brought up and I was brought up, through love of this country.\" Who reportedly spoke these words, in reference to President Barack Obama, at a private group dinner featuring Wisconsin Gov. Scott Walker on February 18, 2015?",
    "answer": "RUDOLPH GIULIANI",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What name was shared by three English monarchs before the Norman Conquest (the Elder, the Martyr, and the Confessor) and by another eight English monarchs after the conquest?",
    "answer": "EDWARD",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "\"Tropical,\" \"Wild Berry,\" \"Sour,\" \"Darkside,\" \"Desserts,\" and a 2014 limited-edition football-themed \"Seattle Mix\" are among the produced varieties of what confection brand?",
    "answer": "SKITTLES",
    "percent_correct": 76.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The plot of what 1998 movie is driven in part by circumstances surrounding brothers named Daniel, Sean, Peter, and James, the last of whom is the only one still alive at the end of the film?",
    "answer": "SAVING PRIVATE RYAN",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What is the standard term in ice hockey for the period of time when one team has more players on the ice than the other team, due to one or more penalties committed by the short-handed team?",
    "answer": "POWER PLAY",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "The influential 15th-century painter born Guido di Pietro took the name Giovanni upon entering the Dominican order in the city of Fiesole, near Florence, around 1418, but is best known by what posthumous nickname?",
    "answer": "FRA ANGELICO",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "As measured by cargo throughput, the second- through fourth-largest shipping ports in Europe are in Antwerp, Hamburg, and Novorossiysk. Europe's largest, equivalent to the next three combined, is the port of what city?",
    "answer": "ROTTERDAM",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the man who replaced Zhao Ziyang as general secretary of the Communist Party of China following the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989, serving in that post until 2002, while also serving as the nation's president from 1993 to 2003.",
    "answer": "JIANG ZEMIN",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Though the term was originally associated with medieval French poetry, ballade was first applied to instrumental music in the 1830s/40s by Ballades No. 1 to 4 , which are considered today among the most technically (and poetically) challenging pieces of the standard piano repertoire. Who composed these ballades?",
    "answer": "FRÉDÉRIC CHOPIN",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "A popular card game, whose object is not to hold the one unmatchable card in the deck at the end, is known in various countries as \"Black Peter\" (in native languages). What is this game's best-known English name?",
    "answer": "OLD MAID",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Though perhaps associated most with rocker Ted Nugent, the pathogen Bartonella henselae is named after scientist Alberto Barton and lab technologist Diane Hensel. It causes a benign infectious disease which is best known colloquially as what?",
    "answer": "CAT SCRATCH FEVER (DISEASE)",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In June, 1974, Wrigley's Juicy Fruit gum was the first product purchased in the United States to feature what innovative  and now widespread technology?",
    "answer": "BAR CODES",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The hip hop artists T.I., Ludacris, Big Boi and André 3000 (of Outkast), B.o.B., Soulja Boy, and Young Jeezy are all most closely associated with what city?",
    "answer": "ATLANTA",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What is the pseudonym—misunderstood during a failed introduction—of the guileless main character in the 1971 Jerzy Kosinski novel Being There ?",
    "answer": "CHAUNCEY GARDINER",
    "percent_correct": 31.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Pulitzer Prizes were first awarded in 1917 by what American university, which administers the awards to this day?",
    "answer": "COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The municipalities of Villa de Guadalupe in Mexico; Paris, France; Lourdes, France; and Fatima, Portugal most distinctively have what in common?",
    "answer": "APPARITIONS OF THE VIRGIN MARY",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "On the cover of the 1969 album palindromically titled Aoxomoxoa , the art displaying the band's name is an ambigram which, reportedly, can also be viewed as \"we ate the acid.\" What is the band's name?",
    "answer": "GRATEFUL DEAD",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the chemical formula of the hydrocarbon that is the primary component of natural gas?",
    "answer": "CH4",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Give the name of any of the men who won one (or more) of the Major Championships in men's golf in the year 2014.",
    "answer": "BUBBA WATSON, MARTIN KAYMER, RORY MCILROY",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "What successful 1988 film was the first of many featuring action roles for an Emmy winner who had theretofore been known primarily as a television comedy actor and, perhaps, wine-cooler pitchman? The film has been described as an interracial buddy movie, though the buddies don't actually meet until after the climax.",
    "answer": "DIE HARD",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "The Québécois dish frite sauce , with the addition of fromage en grains , becomes a dish best known as what?",
    "answer": "POUTINE",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "In the United States, the Bureau of Labor Statistics publishes a measurement of average changes in fees received by originators of all output created domestically, at all stages of processing. The measure is abbreviated PPI , which stands for what?",
    "answer": "PRODUCER PRICE INDEX",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the Czech-born Austrian composer, considered a transitional artist between the Romantic and Modernist periods, who wrote Symphony No. 8 in E-flat Major (\"Symphony of a Thousand\"). The symphony, first performed in 1910, is notable for its massive scale, which can include a gigantic orchestra, eight vocal soloists, a boy's choir, and two adult choirs.",
    "answer": "GUSTAV MAHLER",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The first pop album to produce five singles that all reached #1 on the Billboard Hot 100 chart was Michael Jackson's Bad in 1987. The second album to do so (and the first by a female artist) was released in 2010 by what pop superstar?",
    "answer": "KATY PERRY",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "What is today the common name of the island, ceded to the United States in the 1898 treaty that ended the Spanish-American War, that was originally called Borinquen by its native Taíno people?",
    "answer": "PUERTO RICO",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The main character in Nathanael West's second novel is a male advice columnist for the lovelorn in Depression-era New York who goes by what name?",
    "answer": "MISS LONELYHEARTS",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Actor Alfonso Ribeiro, Olympic skater Meryl Davis, actress Amber Riley, country musician Kellie Pickler, and Green Bay Packers wide receiver Donald Driver all have what most prominently in common?",
    "answer": "DANCING WITH THE STARS CHAMPIONS",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What man, a former peasant and adviser to Tsar Nicholas II and Empress Alexandra, is history's most famous (alleged) elder in the schismatic and ecstatic ritual-practicing Russian Orthodox sect known as Khlysty ?",
    "answer": "GRIGORIY RASPUTIN",
    "percent_correct": 86.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Bertha Franklin, a manager at the Hacienda Motel in south Los Angeles, was found to have committed justifiable homicide in the December 1964 fatal shooting of what 33-year-old pioneering superstar of soul music?",
    "answer": "SAM COOKE",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Name the play by Victorien Sardou, which takes place in a summer month during the French Revolution, that gives its title to a dish created and named in the play's honor upon its premiere in January, 1894. One current recipe for the dish consists of lobster cubes mixed with cream, seasoned with mustard, served in two halves of the shell, sprinkled with cheese, and cooked au gratin .",
    "answer": "THERMIDOR",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Name the man who served as conductor of the Boston Pops Orchestra from 1930 until his death in July 1979.",
    "answer": "ARTHUR FIEDLER",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The medieval counties of Vaduz and Schellenberg (specifically, a countship and lordship, respectively) were united in 1719 to become a sovereign member state of the Holy Roman Empire, and ultimately an independent nation, with what name?",
    "answer": "LIECHTENSTEIN",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The actor Fred Rerun Berry achieved fame primarily as the character \"Rerun\" (which he subsequently adopted as his legal middle name) on what ABC television sitcom, which aired original episodes in the late 1970s, with a syndicated sequel series airing a decade later?",
    "answer": "WHAT'S HAPPENING!!",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "In the late 1980s and early 1990s, the U.S. Senators Alan Cranston, Dennis DeConcini, John Glenn, John McCain, and Donald Riegle were, as a complete set, closely associated with what criminal?",
    "answer": "CHARLES KEATING",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "A law known as the Reinheitsgebot , which originated in the Holy Roman Empire in 1487 and was endorsed more broadly in 1516, famously regulated practices associated with what type of business?",
    "answer": "BEER BREWING",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The Pacific island nations of Fiji, Vanuatu, Solomon Islands, and Papua New Guinea are within a region of Oceania known by what term, derived from the Greek term for \"black islands\"?",
    "answer": "MELANESIA",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Among the famous works of Renaissance painter El Greco are \"views\" of what Spanish city, which was the artist's home from 1577 until his death in 1614?",
    "answer": "TOLEDO",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What term for \"Hungarian\" (as an ethnic group) is also the name of the country's official language, which is the most widely spoken non-Indo-European language in Europe?",
    "answer": "MAGYAR",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Thomas Gradgrind, Nell Trent, Esther Summerson, John Harmon (Rokesmith), and Seth Pecksniff are among the main characters in the works of what author?",
    "answer": "CHARLES DICKENS",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the producer and director, an early pioneer of screen comedy widely credited as the progenitor of slapstick on film, who founded Keystone Studios in 1913 and is also remembered for his \"bathing beauties\" of the era.",
    "answer": "MACK SENNETT",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Twin sons of Ares and Aphrodite, who were the Greek mythological personifications of fear and terror, gave their names (thanks to American astronomer Asaph Hall) to celestial objects that are most closely and uniquely associated with what other celestial object?",
    "answer": "MARS",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Identify the suburb of Portland, Oregon, that best fits in this list of municipalities: Peachtree City, Georgia; Prairie City, Illinois; Gem, Idaho; Centennial, Colorado; Silver Springs, Nevada; Magnolia, Mississippi; Buckeye Lake, Ohio.",
    "answer": "BEAVERTON",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The Battle of Pork Chop Hill, Battle of Heartbreak Ridge, and Battle of the Bowling Alley were engagements fought during what war?",
    "answer": "KOREAN WAR",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "For 17 of 18 weeks from late October 2002 to early March 2003, Billboard magazine's \"Modern Rock\" chart was topped by three songs from three different bands that all shared a member (who served as drummer on two songs and guitarist and lead vocalist on the third). The songs were \"You Know You're Right,\" \"No One Knows,\" and \"All My Life.\" Name the musician who was a member of all three bands.",
    "answer": "DAVE GROHL",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The name of what company is formed from a portmanteau of Danish words that translate to English as \"play well\"?",
    "answer": "LEGO",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "I saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by madness, starving hysterical naked, dragging themselves through the negro streets at dawn looking for an angry fix... Thus begins what influential poem, regarded generally as the anthem of the Beat Generation?",
    "answer": "HOWL",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The 1920 Treaty of Tartu established the borders between what two nations, which held until the treaty was broken by the Winter War of 1939—40?",
    "answer": "FINLAND, RUSSIA",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Squads in the world's premier annual team tennis tournament represent their countries in a battle for a trophy purchased in 1900 by the event's founder, a Harvard student and future U.S. Secretary of War. What is the name of this trophy—and, by extension, event?",
    "answer": "DAVIS CUP",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "The pushy leading character in what stage musical has been portrayed on Broadway by theatre legends Ethel Merman (1959), Angela Lansbury (1975), Tyne Daly (1989), Bernadette Peters (2003), and Patti LuPone (2008)?",
    "answer": "GYPSY",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What is the base shared by the sauces known around the world as nước mắm , patis , nam pla , jeotgal , and colatura d'alici ?",
    "answer": "FISH",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The fictional Amazing Amy series of children's books is based on the childhood of the title character from what popular 2014 film?",
    "answer": "GONE GIRL",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Name the Russian scientist, politician, former first deputy prime minister, and opposition leader who was murdered while walking home from dinner in Moscow late in the evening of February 27, 2015.",
    "answer": "BORIS NEMTSOV",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The medical condition goiter , which is an abnormal enlargement of the thyroid gland causing swelling of the larynx or neck, is most often caused by the dietary lack of what?",
    "answer": "IODINE",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The 2014 running of what prestigious automobile race, which concluded on Sunday, June 15, was won by Swiss Marcel Fässler, Frenchman Benoît Tréluyer, and German André Lotterer?",
    "answer": "24 HOURS OF LE MANS",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "For a period up until the early 1990s, many international maps displayed a diamond-shaped, 4400 mi 2 \"Neutral Zone,\" whose existence was a result of the 1922 Treaty of Muhammarah. Between what two nations did this Neutral Zone sit?",
    "answer": "IRAQ, SAUDI ARABIA",
    "percent_correct": 15.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Organized groups in the British colonies of North America who resisted the Stamp Act, passed by Parliament in 1765, came to be known collectively by what moniker? The groups, who remained active through the collapse of royal authority ten years later, have a name that is similar to (and surely inspired) a modern crime-drama television series.",
    "answer": "SONS OF LIBERTY",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The initiative that aims to establish a set of high-quality academic standards in mathematics and English language arts/literacy in the United States, and is underwritten by the Council of Chief State School Officers and the National Governors Association, is best known by what term?",
    "answer": "COMMON CORE",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "In November 2013, casino empire cofounder Elaine Wynn purchased an oil-on-canvas triptych for over $142 million, setting the world record for art sold at an auction. Identify either the 20th c. Irish-born British artist who painted this triptych or his friend and rival, the 20th c. German-born British artist who is the subject of this work.",
    "answer": "FRANCIS BACON, LUCIEN FREUD",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "As referenced in its title, a bestselling allegorical business book by Dr. Spencer Johnson, published in 1998, specifically addresses the moving of what?",
    "answer": "CHEESE",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What notoriously fickle but high-quality red wine grape variety, one of the three traditional champagne grape varieties (together with Chardonnay and Pinot Meunier), is the cultivar most associated with France's Burgundy region, which is its viticultural home?",
    "answer": "PINOT NOIR",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The Roman Empire's Julio-Claudian dynasty lasted for 95 years, comprising roughly the first half of Pax Romana , from the ascension of Augustus in 27 BC until the suicide of Nero in 68 AD. Name any two of the other three emperors who ruled during the dynasty.",
    "answer": "TIBERIUS, CALIGULA, CLAUDIUS",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "As measured by land area, what is currently the largest country in Europe that was not a part of the USSR?",
    "answer": "FRANCE (DENMARK, TURKEY also accepted)",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Independence Day was not formally celebrated for over 80 years in what southern U.S. city, due to painful memories of the city's fall to Maj. Gen. Ulysses S. Grant's Union forces on July 4, 1863, following a dreadful six-week siege?",
    "answer": "VICKSBURG",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Although he appears on screen only briefly in the movie's first few moments, U.S. Marine PFC William Santiago is central to the storyline of what 1992 film?",
    "answer": "A FEW GOOD MEN",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Give the precise title (in English) of the smash bestselling novel by Haruki Murakami first published in Japanese in 2009, and English in 2011. The title is a play on the Japanese pronunciation of a George Orwell novel.",
    "answer": "1Q84",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "The array pictured here is most commonly named after what Frenchman? Click here",
    "answer": "BLAISE PASCAL",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This montage is representative of the work of what photographer? Click here",
    "answer": "RICHARD AVEDON",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The supernova remnant Messier 1 (better known as the Crab Nebula) and the orange giant star Aldebaran are within what zodiacal constellation, through which the Sun passes from mid-May to late June?",
    "answer": "TAURUS",
    "percent_correct": 23.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Got kind of tired packing and unpacking, / Town to town and up and down the dial / Maybe you and me were never meant to be, / But baby think of me once in awhile. The opening theme of what television sitcom includes these lyrics, which refer to character Andy Travis's decision to settle down after years of moving from job to job?",
    "answer": "WKRP IN CINCINNATI",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Infiniti, first introduced as a brand in the United States in 1989, is the luxury division of what automobile manufacturer?",
    "answer": "NISSAN",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Unguja Island, which sits just off the southeast coast of Africa northwest of Madagascar., is a major producer of the world's supply of cloves and the largest member of an archipelago once known as the Spice Islands. The island is better known by what name?",
    "answer": "ZANZIBAR",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Of the four heads carved into Mount Rushmore, which president's is on the far right?",
    "answer": "ABRAHAM LINCOLN",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "\"There is a kind of merry war betwixt Signior Benedick and her: they never meet but there's a skirmish of wit between them.\" This line is uttered by Leonato in Act I Scene I of what Shakespeare play?",
    "answer": "MUCH ADO ABOUT NOTHING",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "If C = {1,2,3,4,5} and D = {4,5,6}, then C ∩ D = ?",
    "answer": "{4,5}",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Le Pédant joué and L'Autre monde ou les états et empires de la Lune are among the works of what French dramatist and romantic (pictured), who is perhaps best known today for fictional depictions of him in other works? Click here",
    "answer": "CYRANO DE BERGERAC",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Mme Nadezhda von Meck is remembered today for her patronage, as well as her complex and exclusively epistolary relationship, with what composer, who dedicated his Fourth Symphony to her in 1877?",
    "answer": "PYOTR TCHAIKOVSKY",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The staging of a theatrical adaptation of \"What We Talk About When We Talk About Love,\" a short story from a 1981 collection of the same title by Raymond Carver, provides the basis for what Academy Award-winning film?",
    "answer": "BIRDMAN",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Identify the New Jersey university named after the woman who became the first native-born U.S. citizen to be canonized as a saint in the Roman Catholic Church.",
    "answer": "SETON HALL UNIVERSITY",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Of the five teams that have won the Cricket World Cup in its history, four are nations (India, Australia, Pakistan, Sri Lanka), while the fifth is a multinational team known by what name?",
    "answer": "WEST INDIES",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL64",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "If an atom (or group of atoms) gains electrons or loses protons, it becomes a specific type of ion called an anion . What is the term for the opposite—an ion in which an atom loses electrons?",
    "answer": "CATION",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Due to a unique distinction that lasted until his retirement in 1997, long-time NHL center Craig MacTavish is today most closely associated with what ice hockey accoutrement?",
    "answer": "HELMET",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "What is the first name shared by the three female characters in this montage? Click here",
    "answer": "TRIXIE",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Popular native dishes, such as a ubiquitous preparation in the tradition of Japanese musubi , as well as local varieties manufactured exclusively for the state, help make Hawaiians by far the greatest per capita consumers of what food item?",
    "answer": "SPAM",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Toussaint Charbonneau, Sergeant Charles Floyd, Alexander Hamilton Willard, John Ordway, and York are individuals among a group most closely associated in the historical record with what other two men?",
    "answer": "MERIWETHER LEWIS, WILLIAM CLARK",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "A restaurant located at Reisterstown Road and Rogers Avenue near the Pimlico Race Course in northwest Baltimore provided the title, and the basis, for what 1982 film?",
    "answer": "DINER",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 1,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "This city was a royal residence of Charlemagne in the 8th c., the coronation location of Holy Roman Emperors from the 16th c. until the empire's dissolution in 1806, the seat of the diet of the German Confederation in the 19th c., and today the main world financial center of continental Europe. Name the city.",
    "answer": "FRANKFURT",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Seymour, Audrey, Mushnik, and—most distinctively—Audrey II are main characters in what stage musical?",
    "answer": "LITTLE SHOP OF HORRORS",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "What Renaissance literary figure, often called the \"Father of Humanism\", is also widely considered the first modern poet, due to his mastery of the sonnet form, as evidenced (for example) by works in Il Canzoniere ?",
    "answer": "PETRARCH",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The period of British history that began in 1660—a period which started with Charles II's reclamation of the crown of England and ended with the ascension of William and Mary during the Glorious Revolution—is best known by what one-word term?",
    "answer": "RESTORATION",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Freedom Williams, Martha Wash, and Zelma Davis were among the vocalists hired by dance-pop producers David Cole and Robert Clivillés to be featured on the producers' early 1990s singles, in a project that went by what name?",
    "answer": "C+C MUSIC FACTORY",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What, precisely, is the mass of the platinum-iridium cylinder currently held under strict supervision at the Bureau International des Poids et Mesures in the Parc de Saint-Cloud, at Sèvres, France?",
    "answer": "ONE KILOGRAM",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 2,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "What U.S. Senator was the primary legislative sponsor of the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997, as well as the namesake for one of the law's best known and most enduring creations?",
    "answer": "WILLIAM ROTH",
    "percent_correct": 37.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "In statistics, the distribution that expresses the probability of a given number of independent events occurring within a time interval (if these events occur with a known frequency) is named after what French mathematician?",
    "answer": "SIMÉON DENIS POISSON",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the political party which manifested from an Islamic ideology of the 1930s espousing Marxist social analysis, nationalism, and unification of the Arab world. It would eventually become the ruling party of Iraq and Syria (and still leads the latter).",
    "answer": "BA'ATH PARTY",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "While it means literally \"little ear\", the term auricle in older medical texts referred to another specific and unrelated part of anatomy. What is the term now in standard usage, replacing auricle (which now applies to something else, nearby and related, but different)?",
    "answer": "ATRIUM",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "There are paintings by this English portraitist in almost all major art museums in the United States and Great Britain, including his masterful portrait of (possibly) merchant's son Jonathan Buttall at The Huntington in San Marino, California. Name the artist.",
    "answer": "THOMAS GAINSBOROUGH",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "1814's Waverley , the first of the long series of namesake romantic \"Waverley Novels\", was the work of what author?",
    "answer": "SIR WALTER SCOTT",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 3,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "While led since 1993 by Prime Ministers Manuel Esquivel, Said Musa, and Dean Barrow, Queen Elizabeth II, represented by Governor-General Colville Young, is the official head of state of what Latin American nation?",
    "answer": "BELIZE",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "General Growth Properties, Westfield Corporation, Mills Corporation, and Simon Property Group are (or were) all companies which focus primarily on what specific type of business?",
    "answer": "SHOPPING MALLS",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Plays by New York Giants center fielder Willie Mays in the 1954 World Series, San Francisco 49ers wide receiver Dwight Clark in the 1982 NFC Championship, and New York Mets left fielder Endy Chávez in the 2006 NLCS, are each known today by what generic term?",
    "answer": "THE CATCH",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "What was the first Confederate state capital city to be lost to the Union during the U.S. Civil War, as a result of the fall of Fort Donelson to Brig. Gen. Ulysses S. Grant in February, 1862?",
    "answer": "NASHVILLE",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "In its best-known form, chalk is (nearly) pure calcium carbonate. The special drawing chalk cut from a red ochre variety of hematite is most commonly called what, directly from the French for \"blood-red\"?",
    "answer": "SANGUINE",
    "percent_correct": 16.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "British Prime Minister David Cameron's Conservative Party won an absolute majority in the UK's 2015 general election, gaining him the right to govern without a coalition partner. In his first term, he governed in coalition with what centrist party, which won only eight of the 650 seats in the House of Commons in the recent election (down from a previous 56)?",
    "answer": "LIBERAL DEMOCRAT",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 4,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "What is the name of this doll? Click here",
    "answer": "RAGGEDY ANN",
    "percent_correct": 97.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the frenzied and fast-paced musical comedy film from 1964 whose loose plot involves four musicians preparing for a London television appearance while minding a mischievous grandfather.",
    "answer": "A HARD DAY'S NIGHT",
    "percent_correct": 54.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The most watched television series in the U.S. for the 2013-14 season outside the four major networks (ABC, CBS, Fox, NBC)—and #1 among all networks for adults 18-49—was what epic drama series, which airs original episodes Sundays at 9:00pm ET on AMC?",
    "answer": "THE WALKING DEAD",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The decay of uranium, the most radioactive element in the earth's crust, gives rise to essentially all other radioactive elements in nature, before its final decay into what common, heavy, stable element?",
    "answer": "LEAD",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "Jacopo Tintoretto, Salvador Dalí, Peter Paul Rubens, Andrea del Castagno, and Lucas Cranach the Elder all painted works of a specific event that was depicted most famously by what other artist?",
    "answer": "LEONARDO DA VINCI (The Last Supper) or MICHELANGELO (Pieta)",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "In the history of the city of New York,  there have been four mayors who have served for three successive four-year terms (making them the city's longest-serving). The most recent was Michael Bloomberg; give the last names of any two of the other three.",
    "answer": "LA GUARDIA, WAGNER, KOCH",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 5,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Kumis , leben , kefir , chal , and shubat are all regional culinary items made from what?",
    "answer": "MILK",
    "percent_correct": 64.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "His Norman Mailer Prize for Lifetime Achievement, won in 2014, is the most recent of the numerous prestigious awards won by what American novelist, whose latest works include the short story collection The Angel Esmeralda and the novels Point Omega , Falling Man , and Cosmopolis ?",
    "answer": "DON DELILLO",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Identify the musical instrument pictured here, a member of the zither family used commonly in the music of Appalachia. Click here",
    "answer": "DULCIMER",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The Order of Friars Minor, also known simply as the Franciscans, is headquartered in what Italian comune , which was the birthplace of the order's founder in (or around) 1181?",
    "answer": "ASSISI",
    "percent_correct": 71.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the botanical term, derived from the Latin for \"little foot,\" for the stalk that attaches a plant's leaf blade ( lamina ) to its stem?",
    "answer": "PETIOLE",
    "percent_correct": 8.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The song \"See You Again,\" featured in the 2015 film Furious 7 and written as a tribute to the late actor Paul Walker, set streaming and download records while shooting to the top of the Billboard chart in concurrence with the film's release. What hip hop artist recorded the song, which also featured the song's writer, Charlie Puth?",
    "answer": "WIZ KHALIFA",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 6,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the 1975 National Medal of Science recipient who was chief architect of the Saturn V rocket launch vehicle program in the late 1960s/early 1970s, as well as a central participant in Operation Paperclip and Projekt Amerika in the 1940s.",
    "answer": "WERNHER VON BRAUN",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Amora, Plochman's, Händlmaier, Colman's, and Gulden's are among the notable brands of what food product?",
    "answer": "MUSTARD",
    "percent_correct": 81.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The American patriotic song \"My Country 'Tis of Thee\" (\"America\") is sung to the tune of a national anthem, the world's oldest, first sung in 1745. What is the title of that anthem?",
    "answer": "GOD SAVE THE KING/QUEEN",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Among the 48 U.S. states officially subdivided into counties, Delaware has the fewest, with three. Georgia has the second-most, with 159—what state has the most, with 254?",
    "answer": "TEXAS",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "An ancient Greek term combining the words for \"under\" and \"length\" provides the etymology for what geometric term, common in relation to triangles?",
    "answer": "HYPOTENUSE",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the 7th c. BCE Athenian legislator who is famous today for his harsh and wildly unpopular codification of the law, which declared death the penalty for most offenses.",
    "answer": "DRACO",
    "percent_correct": 56.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 7,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Name the English poet who authored the 1821 pastoral elegy Adonaïs , or the fellow poet and friend whom the elegy memorialized.",
    "answer": "PERCY BYSSHE SHELLEY, JOHN KEATS",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the most common name of the largest object in the region of the solar system known as the Kuiper belt (excepting Eris, which may be in the belt or the \"scattered disc,\" depending on the source)?",
    "answer": "PLUTO",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "Name the French fashion designer whose designs included the \"H\" line and \"A\" line and who first achieved worldwide fame in 1947 with his long-skirted \"New Look\" (pictured). Click here",
    "answer": "CHRISTIAN DIOR",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Dr. Tim Whatley, Babu Bhatt, Jake Jarmel, Marla Penny, Rebecca DeMornay, and Ruthie Cohen were minor characters in what television series?",
    "answer": "SEINFELD",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Irish composer and pianist John Field is widely considered the initiator of what type of musical composition? Evocatively dreamy and pensive, the form was mastered famously by Frédéric Chopin's 21 compositions of the style, including what may be the best known of all his works, Op. 9, No. 2 .",
    "answer": "NOCTURNE",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What begins in Furtwangen im Schwarzwald, a small city in the Black Forest region of far southwestern Germany, and ends on the Black Sea coast, roughly around the Romania/Ukraine border?",
    "answer": "DANUBE",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 8,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "With over 2,600 stores in 34 states, what supermarket chain is the largest in the U.S. by revenue? In addition to its namesake banner, it also operates stores under the names Dillons, Fred Meyer, Fry's, King Soopers, Owen's, QFC, Ralphs, Smith's, and others.",
    "answer": "KROGER",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "The Adi Granth , compiled by Arjan Dev Ji in the early 17th c., is a text revered today (in expanded modern form) by followers of what religion?",
    "answer": "SIKHISM",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The highest peak in New Zealand, the strait that separates that country's North and South Islands, and an island nation in the South Pacific associated with New Zealand are all named after what navigator?",
    "answer": "JAMES COOK",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "In April, 2015, Pope Francis kindled a diplomatic confrontation by describing as \"the first genocide of the 20th century\" the \"senseless slaughter\" during WWI of members of what ethnic group?",
    "answer": "ARMENIANS",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "While the origination of this phrase is sometimes credited to Common Sense , it never actually appeared in Thomas Paine's pamphlet. Rather, its first documentary evidence appears in an article in a March 1776 edition of The Virginia Gazette , anonymously signed \"A PLANTER\". What is this very familiar, nationally known phrase?",
    "answer": "UNITED STATES OF AMERICA",
    "percent_correct": 13.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "What pop music superstar, early in his career, wrote commercial jingles for Band-Aid (\"I am stuck on Band-Aid, 'cause Band-Aid's stuck on me\"), Stridex (\"Give your face something to smile about with Stridex...\"), State Farm (\"Like a good neighbor, State Farm is there\"), and McDonald's (\"You Deserve a Break Today\")?",
    "answer": "BARRY MANILOW",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 9,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the term for the technique of using ultrasound, X-rays, or other penetrating waves to procure diagnostic images of structures deep within a body via sectioning? It is the \"T\" in CAT scan .",
    "answer": "TOMOGRAPHY",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "Goldbach's conjecture , which Christian Goldbach first made in a letter to Leonhard Euler in 1742, states that every even integer greater than two can be expressed as the sum of two what?",
    "answer": "PRIME NUMBERS",
    "percent_correct": 60.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LIFESTYLE",
    "question_text": "What American car model takes its name from a small warship designed for convoy escort duties during WWII? Prior to that, it was a three-masted, single gun-decked sailing vessel.",
    "answer": "CORVETTE",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This artistic term for a very small painting (typically applied to portraits and manuscript illuminations) is not actually related to the Latin for \"tiny,\" but rather derives from a word for a pigment known today as red lead. What is the artistic term?",
    "answer": "MINIATURE",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Cheap and large-scale mass production of steel brought about the end of commercial production for what tough and malleable ferrous alloy, a form of which was used to produce the Eiffel Tower, the gates of Westminster Abbey, and the armature of the Statue of Liberty?",
    "answer": "WROUGHT IRON",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What six-time MVP and twenty-three-time NHL All-Star was the oldest player, by far , on the roster of the 1979-80 Hartford Whalers?",
    "answer": "GORDIE HOWE",
    "percent_correct": 50.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 10,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The chanter , chanter reed , and drone are among the components that make up what musical instrument?",
    "answer": "BAGPIPES",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "The two tone movement and musical genre, as represented by the music of the 2 Tone Records label and popular in Britain in the late 1970s, combined components of punk rock with traditional elements from what other musical genre?",
    "answer": "SKA/REGGAE",
    "percent_correct": 48.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The 13th c. military leader and civil administrator named Tolui, also known as Jui-Tsung, is remembered today (if he's remembered at all) for his famous father and famous son. Give the name of either.",
    "answer": "GENGHIS KHAN, KUBLAI KHAN",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Naturally occurring dyes include cochineal , a red dye made from crushed insects, logwood and madder produced from plants, and what other plant-based dye, extremely common for use in blue jean denim and food colorant FD&C Blue No. 2?",
    "answer": "INDIGO",
    "percent_correct": 74.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "What is the term (Greek for \"long\") for the diacritic used to mark a long vowel? It consists of a straight bar placed above a letter.",
    "answer": "MACRON",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the duo, subjects of a \"New Hollywood\" film from 1967, who died 33 years earlier in Bienville Parish, Louisiana.",
    "answer": "BONNIE (PARKER) & CLYDE (BARROW)",
    "percent_correct": 89.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 11,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Of the 20 (or so) municipalities in the United States with this name, Ohio's is the most populous, Maryland's is the oldest, and Mississippi's is the most literary, but their namesake in England surpasses them in all three areas. What's the name?",
    "answer": "OXFORD",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "As hero troops, the Archer Queen and Barbarian King are the most powerful troops in what video game, which also features Goblins, Wall Breakers, P.E.K.K.As, Hog Riders, and Lava Hounds?",
    "answer": "CLASH OF CLANS",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Known as il prete rosso (\"the redheaded priest\"), as he was educated both for music and the priesthood, this prodigious Italian Baroque composer's extant works include 500-odd concertos (including a famous tetralogy within Opus 8 ), 49 operas (including Tito Manlio , said to be completed in five days), as well as numerous cantatas, oratorios, and motets. Name this composer.",
    "answer": "ANTONIO VIVALDI",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "\"Almost Paradise... Love Theme from Footloose\" was a 1984 smash duet by singers Mike Reno and Ann Wilson, who at the time were members of what other two bands?",
    "answer": "LOVERBOY, HEART",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "While Kirsch is a brandy made from fermented cherries, Cognac is made from grapes, and Slivovitz from plums, what fruit is used to produce Calvados ?",
    "answer": "APPLES",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Supercell, squall line, multi-cell, and single-cell—these are the four standard classifications (listed in order of severity) of what specific scientific phenomenon?",
    "answer": "THUNDERSTORMS",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 12,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Fill in the blank (diacriticals not required): yî, èr, sân, sì, wŭ, liù, ____, bâ, jiŭ, shí .",
    "answer": "QÎ",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Popular spinoffs of The Oprah Winfrey Show have included programs hosted by psychologist Dr. Phil McGraw, celebrity chef Rachael Ray, cardiothoracic surgeon Dr. Mehmet Oz, and what Chicago-based interior decorator?",
    "answer": "NATE BERKUS",
    "percent_correct": 25.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "\"Fasten your seat belts. It's going to be a bumpy night.\" This line, one of the most famous in cinematic history, is uttered at a party by the hostess, Margo Channing, in what film?",
    "answer": "ALL ABOUT EVE",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "What country, a U.N. member, is a principality ruled by co-princes, currently Joan Enric Vives Sicília and François Hollande (who are also the Bishop of Urgell and the president of France, respectively)?",
    "answer": "ANDORRA",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What National Basketball Association franchise has most recently relocated to a new state, having moved to its present home for the 2012-2013 season (returning to the state where it played from 1968 to 1977)?",
    "answer": "BROOKLYN NETS",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Secret negotiations in Oslo in 1993 led to a historic agreement signed at a public ceremony in Washington in September of that year, hosted by President Bill Clinton and attended by what two world leaders, representing the two sides of negotiations?",
    "answer": "YITZHAK RABIN, YASSER ARAFAT",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 13,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the term for the electromagnet formed by a cylindrical coil of wire when an electric current is passed through it, creating a magnetic field that magnetizes an iron rod placed on its axis? One example is used to relay energy from a car battery to a starter motor.",
    "answer": "SOLENOID",
    "percent_correct": 26.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "What is the name for the branch of physics that deals with the transformation of heat into, and from, other forms of energy? The term, first used by Lord Kelvin in the mid-19th c.,  is derived in part from the Greek for \"heat.\"",
    "answer": "THERMODYNAMICS",
    "percent_correct": 87.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Everton F.C., which has competed in the top division of English soccer for a record 110 seasons (and continuously since 1954), has, since 1892, played its home fixtures at Goodison Park, which is located in what city?",
    "answer": "LIVERPOOL",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "What is the most common Japanese name for the item the youngster is holding in this photo? Click here",
    "answer": "NORI",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "In October 1990, a jury famously acquitted Dennis Barrie, director of the Contemporary Arts Center in Cincinnati, of obscenity charges stemming from an exhibition of pictures by what American photographer?",
    "answer": "ROBERT MAPPLETHORPE",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Willow Rosenberg, Tabitha Stephens, and sisters Prue, Piper, and Phoebe Halliwell were all TV characters who were most distinctive for being what?",
    "answer": "WITCHES",
    "percent_correct": 85.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 14,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "The Russian phrase Do svidaniya translates idiomatically to what in English?",
    "answer": "GOODBYE",
    "percent_correct": 58.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The contents of a box, labeled \"1952\" and found inside the basement of an old animation building at Walt Disney Studios in Burbank, California, served as inspiration (and provided the working title) for what popular 2015 film?",
    "answer": "TOMORROWLAND",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Over the course of the 1960s, what was created on the border of Egypt and Sudan, and named after Egypt's second president, causing the resettlement of over 100,000 Nubians?",
    "answer": "LAKE NASSER",
    "percent_correct": 22.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Similar in preparation to Salisbury steak , the method of cooking a steak by grinding the beef and shaping it into a flat round patty before grilling (or frying) is said to be a style associated with what European port city?",
    "answer": "HAMBURG",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "What was the name of the influential (though largely useless) Geneva-based organization created by the Treaty of Versailles in 1919?",
    "answer": "LEAGUE OF NATIONS",
    "percent_correct": 87.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Sgt. Suzanne (or Leanne) \"Pepper\" Anderson of the LAPD's Criminal Conspiracy Unit was the main character in what is generally considered to be the first successful dramatic TV series featuring a female in the title role. What was the name of that series?",
    "answer": "POLICE WOMAN",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 15,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Silent Spring , by Rachel Carson; In Cold Blood , by Truman Capote; Eichmann in Jerusalem: A Report on the Banality of Evil , by Hannah Arendt; and \"Letter from a Region in My Mind\" (an essay that forms half of The Fire Next Time ), by James Baldwin: These works all appeared, wholly or serially, in what publication?",
    "answer": "THE NEW YORKER",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "The United Fruit Company, formed in 1899, held monopolistic power in much of Central America, and contributed greatly (and in many cases, negatively) to the national politics of the region, particularly in countries that came to be known as \"banana republics\" due to the company's influence. After a series of mergers and acquisitions, UFC is now what successor company?",
    "answer": "CHIQUITA (BRANDS INTERNATIONAL)",
    "percent_correct": 57.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "This is a screenshot from what film? Click here",
    "answer": "SPIRITED AWAY",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Michiko Kakutani, who has been on staff at the New York Times since 1979, and in her current role since 1983, was awarded a Pulitzer Prize in 1998 in what category?",
    "answer": "CRITICISM",
    "percent_correct": 28.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "1963's \"Green, Green\"; 1973's \"Panama Red\"; 1983's \"Blue Monday\"; 1989's \"Didn't I (Blow Your Mind)\"; 1993's \"7\"; 1996's \"Hit Me Off\"; and 1998's \"You Get What You Give\" are songs by bands that all have what word in their names?",
    "answer": "NEW",
    "percent_correct": 59.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The 2001 EDSA Revolution was a political protest in January of that year resulting in the peaceful overthrow of President Joseph Estrada, who was the 13th president of what nation?",
    "answer": "PHILIPPINES",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 16,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "The transformation of a men's shoe factory in the East Midlands of England into one that produces women's footwear, but catering to men, is the central plotline to what Tony award-winning Broadway musical?",
    "answer": "KINKY BOOTS",
    "percent_correct": 63.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "While there were a small number of fatalities in numerous countries, including the United States, the vast majority of victims in the 2014 Ebola outbreak in West Africa occurred in three countries. Name any one of these three countries.",
    "answer": "GUINEA, LIBERIA, SIERRA LEONE",
    "percent_correct": 79.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Political adviser, U.S. Air Force veteran, and civil rights figure James Howard Meredith is a 1963 graduate of what university?",
    "answer": "UNIVERSITY OF MISSISSIPPI",
    "percent_correct": 33.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "CLASS MUSIC",
    "question_text": "Pictured here is the chorus to what song (lyrics redacted), written in 1908 and first performed in the manner most associated with the song in the early 1930s? Click here",
    "answer": "TAKE ME OUT TO THE BALL GAME",
    "percent_correct": 55.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The 1884 Treaty of Valparaiso, at the end of the four-year War of the Pacific, resulted in the complete loss of sea coastline for what country, which has remained landlocked ever since?",
    "answer": "BOLIVIA",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "Name the 1994 film whose plot is constructed in four segments, three of which are titled \"The Gold Watch,\" \"The Bonnie Situation,\" and \"The Diner.\"",
    "answer": "PULP FICTION",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 17,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The name of Boris Badenov, a Pottsylvanian villain in the Rocky and Bullwinkle cartoons of the 1960s, is a play on that of a tsar who was title character of an 1831 play and an 1873 opera. Identify the author/composer of either work.",
    "answer": "ALEKSANDR PUSHKIN, MODEST MUSSORGSKY",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Carados, Claudin, Erec, Hector de Maris, Lionel, Pelleas, and Tor are lesser-known literary characters among a group that is best known, collectively, as what?",
    "answer": "KNIGHTS OF THE ROUND TABLE",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "Dramas that were an hour-and-a-half in length were the distinctive trademark (evidenced by its title) of what acclaimed and influential anthology series that aired on CBS in the 1950s?",
    "answer": "PLAYHOUSE 90",
    "percent_correct": 18.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "\"Melissa,\" \"I Love You,\" \"Klez,\" \"Nimda,\" \"Oompa-A,\" and \"Anna Kournikova\" are all famous examples of what?",
    "answer": "COMPUTER VIRUSES",
    "percent_correct": 44.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "In April 1992, the surviving members of what rock band were joined by a surfeit of stars for a widely broadcast memorial concert at London's Wembley Stadium, at a time when the band was (unrelatedly) enjoying a resurgence in popularity in the U.S., thanks to the film Wayne's World ?",
    "answer": "QUEEN",
    "percent_correct": 77.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The region of Imperial Russia known as the Pale , which existed from the late 18th c. until the fall of the empire in 1917, is historically significant for the residency there of what group?",
    "answer": "JEWS",
    "percent_correct": 35.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 18,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "This is the work of what Post-Impressionist? Click here",
    "answer": "PAUL CEZANNE",
    "percent_correct": 40.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "On a list of the largest countries in Africa by area, ranked from biggest to smallest, Algeria moved from second to first in July, 2011. What historical event caused this promotion?",
    "answer": "INDEPENDENCE OF SOUTH SUDAN",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "A character from ancient mythology, a sculptor, fell in love with a statue he carved and was granted the wish that it come to life by Aphrodite. This character provided the inspiration — and the title — for what play, which premiered in 1913?",
    "answer": "PYGMALION",
    "percent_correct": 62.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The hijinks of an eager-to-please but hapless Jewish nurse and a Long Island Christian family that witnesses and endures the hijinks are central to the plot of what 2000 comedy film?",
    "answer": "MEET THE PARENTS",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "Name the man who was, beginning in 1919, president of the exiled Korean Provisional Government during the Imperial Japanese rule of Korea, and three decades later became the first elected president of South Korea, a position he would hold until his resignation in 1960.",
    "answer": "SYNGMAN RHEE",
    "percent_correct": 21.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "The New York Jets defensive foursome of Mark Gastineau, Joe Klecko, Marty Lyons, and Abdul Salaam were given what moniker in the early 1980s in honor of their talent for tackling the opposing quarterback behind the line of scrimmage before he is able to throw a pass?",
    "answer": "NEW YORK SACK EXCHANGE",
    "percent_correct": 24.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 19,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "Satirae , Epodes , Ars Poetica , and Odes , the latter of which contains the famous aphorism \"carpe diem,\" are among the enduring works of what leading Roman lyric poet of the Augustan age?",
    "answer": "HORACE",
    "percent_correct": 27.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "What is the common name for the modern jazz style, a blending of jazz and classical music, that emerged in the late 1940s/early 1950s as a softer and more reserved alternative to bebop? Associated with West Coast jazz, its \"prince\" was Chet Baker and its birth was captured on a Miles Davis album released in 1957.",
    "answer": "COOL JAZZ",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "Sugarloaf Mountain is the English name of a prominent peak that contributes to the distinctive skyline of what harbor city?",
    "answer": "RIO DE JANEIRO",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "A dead horse on a piano, ants emerging from the palm of a man's hand, and —most famously— a razor slicing open an eyeball are all images from what work of surrealistic cinema?",
    "answer": "UN CHIEN ANDALOU",
    "percent_correct": 32.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "Rafael Esquivel, Nicolas Leoz, Jeffrey Webb, Jack Warner, Eduardo Li, Eugenio Figueredo and Jose Maria Marin are individuals most closely associated with what international organization?",
    "answer": "FIFA",
    "percent_correct": 78.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "In October 1971, a lavish party was held in celebration of an imperial 2,500-year anniversary. The festivities, considered the most lavish banquet in modern history, lasted five days, required 10 years of planning, cost a reported $100 million, and were a factor in the host's eventual abdication. Who was the host of this celebration, which did leave an enduring legacy despite its gross excess?",
    "answer": "MOHAMMAD REZA SHAH PAHLAVI OF IRAN",
    "percent_correct": 38.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 20,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "In the classic version of the board game Stratego , there are four pieces with exactly one available per player: the Marshal, the General, the Flag, and what other piece? A relatively weak piece, it can only defeat the Marshal (or capture the flag); if it attacks any other piece, or is attacked by any piece, it is defeated.",
    "answer": "SPY",
    "percent_correct": 52.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "Of the eight battleships damaged during the December 7, 1941, attack on the U.S. naval base at Pearl Harbor, four were sunk, and one was never raised, her wreckage still lying today at the bottom of the harbor. What is the name of that ship, where 1,177 officers and crewmen were killed?",
    "answer": "USS ARIZONA",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "Name the sweetmeat confection, a specialty of southeastern France (where it is one of the traditional Provencal \"thirteen Christmas desserts\"), whose original ancient Roman recipe was based on honey, walnuts, and eggs. Its modern mass-produced version, such as in ZERO candy bars and Salted Nut Rolls, is rather different.",
    "answer": "NOUGAT",
    "percent_correct": 66.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Mitochondria , chloroplasts , lysosomes , ribosomes , and nuclei are examples of discrete and specialized functional structures within living cells, structures that are best known by what biological term?",
    "answer": "ORGANELLES",
    "percent_correct": 51.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The South China city of Guangzhou, the country's third-most-populous city and the economic and manufacturing hub of the Pearl River Delta, has for much of its history been known by what Romanized name, which is still somewhat common (particularly in its adjectival form)?",
    "answer": "CANTON",
    "percent_correct": 47.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "In the semi-autobiographical Eugene Trilogy , whose three plays premiered on Broadway in the mid-1980s, the central character, Eugene Jerome is the alter-ego of what playwright?",
    "answer": "NEIL SIMON",
    "percent_correct": 36.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 21,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "A jazz supergroup of sorts, which included saxophonist Branford Marsalis, Weather Report drummer Omar Hakim, prolific session bassist Darryl Jones, and classical jazz keyboardist Kenny Kirkland, was assembled as the studio and touring band for the smash 1985 debut solo album by what pop and rock superstar?",
    "answer": "STING",
    "percent_correct": 30.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "While she has appeared on such shows as Fear Factor , The Surreal Life , Girls Behaving Badly , and Plastic Surgery: Before & After , this reality TV star first achieved fame as the shrewd villain in the first season of the NBC reality show The Apprentice . She is known today by her first name, which is what?",
    "answer": "OMAROSA",
    "percent_correct": 61.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "MATH",
    "question_text": "A curve joining all points around two foci such that the sum of the distances from those fixed points is always constant — thus defines what conic section?",
    "answer": "ELLIPSE",
    "percent_correct": 49.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The war known as the First Indochina War was fought between the Viet Minh and French forces, while in the Second Indochina War (a.k.a. the Vietnam War), North Vietnam fought United States-led forces. The Third Indochina War, by far the shortest and least bloody of the three, was fought in 1979 between Vietnam and what other country?",
    "answer": "CHINA/CAMBODIA",
    "percent_correct": 72.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The Galactic Empire series, Foundation series, and Robot series are among the more than 300 volumes published by what science fiction author and member of the biochemistry faculty at Boston University?",
    "answer": "ISAAC ASIMOV",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The 1994 Peter Jackson-directed film Heavenly Creatures , which interprets the story of a murder case involving two girls in 1952 in New Zealand, was the feature film debut of what future Oscar, Grammy, and Emmy winner?",
    "answer": "KATE WINSLET",
    "percent_correct": 45.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 22,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "What current Miami Marlin holds the Major League Baseball record for most consecutive seasons with 200 or more base hits (10) and is the active leader for five-hit games (seven), stolen bases (493), and singles (2,348)?",
    "answer": "ICHIRO SUZUKI",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "ART",
    "question_text": "What is the term from art and printmaking for the process of transferring an image, in paint or ink, from the surface on which it is drawn or painted (e.g. metal or glass) to a sheet of paper (or other surface), creating one unique copy — as the name implies?",
    "answer": "MONOTYPE/MONOPRINT",
    "percent_correct": 17.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "The stories collected in Arabian Nights , which include the tales of Aladdin, Ali Baba and the Forty Thieves, and Sinbad, are framed by a story in which a Persian king's wife delays her execution by telling these tales over the course of 1,001 nights. What was her name?",
    "answer": "SCHEHERAZADE",
    "percent_correct": 68.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "Chloroquine , mefloquine , quinidine , and atovaquone-proguanil are all drugs indicated for the treatment of what disease?",
    "answer": "MALARIA",
    "percent_correct": 75.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "AMER HIST",
    "question_text": "The Cabinet of the President of the United States includes the Vice President and the heads of 15 executive departments. Fourteen are listed here. Name the one that is missing: Attorney General and the Secretaries of the Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Education, Energy, Health and Human Services, Housing and Urban Development, Interior, Labor, State, Transportation, Treasury, and Veterans Affairs.",
    "answer": "SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY",
    "percent_correct": 69.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "TELEVISION",
    "question_text": "The Tangiers, Rampart, Eclipse, Mediterranean, Whiskey Town, and Pike's Gambling Hall are all casinos that appear in what TV series that premiered in 2000?",
    "answer": "CSI: CRIME SCENE INVESTIGATION",
    "percent_correct": 39.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 23,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "BUS/ECON",
    "question_text": "Identify this man. Click here",
    "answer": "TIM COOK",
    "percent_correct": 73.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "FILM",
    "question_text": "The aggressive, condescending, and arrogant Yankees are the victors at the end of what rowdy and vulgar 1976 film comedy?",
    "answer": "THE BAD NEWS BEARS",
    "percent_correct": 53.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "CURR EVENTS",
    "question_text": "The jihadist group in northeastern Nigeria known officially as Jama'atu Ahlis Sunna Lidda'Awati Wal-Jihad (People Committed to the Propagation of the Prophet's Teachings and Jihad) is better known internationally by what name, which translates loosely into English as \"Western education is forbidden\"?",
    "answer": "BOKO HARAM",
    "percent_correct": 80.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "El Grito de Dolores , the anniversary of which is celebrated as Mexican Independence Day, was a famous speech calling on the Mexican people to rebel against peninsulares and the Spanish colonial government. Name the Roman Catholic priest and revolutionary who gave this speech on September 16, 1810.",
    "answer": "DON MIGUEL HIDALGO",
    "percent_correct": 14.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "POP MUSIC",
    "question_text": "According to the lyrics of Billboard magazine's No. 1 country song for 2013, \"In this brand new Chevy with a lift kit, would look a hell of a lot better with you up in it, so baby you a song, you make me wanna roll my windows down and…\" what?",
    "answer": "CRUISE",
    "percent_correct": 29.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "GEOGRAPHY",
    "question_text": "The MacArthur, Julia Tuttle, John F. Kennedy, Broad, and Rickenbacker Causeways all span what bay?",
    "answer": "BISCAYNE BAY",
    "percent_correct": 20.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 24,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "GAMES/SPORT",
    "question_text": "Jack Sock, Sam Querrey, Donald Young, Steve Johnson, and Tim Smyczek are among the highest-ranked Americans internationally in what sport?",
    "answer": "TENNIS",
    "percent_correct": 43.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 1,
    "category": "WORLD HIST",
    "question_text": "The Pact of Steel , known formally (in English) as the Pact of Friendship and Alliance , was an agreement between what two countries, formalized in May 1939 and canceled effectively in 1943?",
    "answer": "GERMANY, ITALY",
    "percent_correct": 41.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 2,
    "category": "LITERATURE",
    "question_text": "A kigo , kireji , and a ternary set of 17 on are among the strictly defined characteristics of what, as mastered by Matsuo Basho?",
    "answer": "HAIKU",
    "percent_correct": 42.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 3,
    "category": "LANGUAGE",
    "question_text": "Most speakers of the Amharic language, the second-most-spoken Semitic language in the world after Arabic, are citizens of (or emigrants from) what country?",
    "answer": "ETHIOPIA",
    "percent_correct": 34.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 4,
    "category": "THEATRE",
    "question_text": "Also called equity light after the stage actors' labor union that mandated its use, what is the most common, superstition-influenced name for the light that is left illuminated on a stage when a theatre is unoccupied?",
    "answer": "GHOST LIGHT",
    "percent_correct": 46.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 5,
    "category": "SCIENCE",
    "question_text": "The bird species photographed here, Icterus galbula , is associated with (and commonly named after) what city, because of the bird's distinctive coloring? Click here",
    "answer": "BALTIMORE",
    "percent_correct": 82.0
  },
  {
    "season": "LL65",
    "match_day": 25,
    "question_number": 6,
    "category": "FOOD/DRINK",
    "question_text": "A controversial technique known as gavage is widely used in the production of what food product?",
    "answer": "FOIE GRAS",
    "percent_correct": 70.0
  }
]